<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Political News on Fox News</title>
    <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics</link>
    <description>Read all about the political news happening with Fox News. Learn about political parties, political campaigns, and international politics today.</description>
    <copyright>Copyright 2024 FOX News Network</copyright>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 12:27:55 -0500</pubDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://global.fncstatic.com/static/orion/styles/img/fox-news/logos/fox-news-desktop.png</url>
      <title>Latest Political News on Fox News</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics</link>
    </image>
    <atom:link rel="self" href="https://moxie.foxnews.com/google-publisher/politics.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"/>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/dem-campaign-tiktok-platform-national-security-threat</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/dem-campaign-tiktok-platform-national-security-threat</guid>
      <title>Dem launches campaign TikTok account, after suggesting the platform 'may be' a national security threat</title>
      <description>Democrat Rep. Ruben Gallego launched an account on TikTok to promote his Senate campaign after suggesting there &amp;apos;may be&amp;apos; national security concerns on the platform.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Rep. Ruben Gallego, D-Ariz., launched a TikTok account for his 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/elections" target="_blank"&gt;Senate campaign&lt;/a&gt;, despite having a history of expressing national security concerns over the platform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Gallego, who is running for the&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/senate" target="_blank"&gt; Senate&lt;/a&gt; seat held by independent Sen. Kyrsten Sinema, previously said that TikTok "may be" a national security threat.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"It may be. There are a lot of ways that we can actually stop TikTok from taking personal information and using it," Gallego told CNN in 2020. "The Chinese, what they like to do, is gather as much information for use in the future."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 2023, Gallego voiced that he was interested in joining the House committee on China, and specifically named TikTok as an entity they would look into.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/vulnerable-dem-senator-tiktok-account-serious-ccp-ties" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VULNERABLE DEM SENATOR PROMOTES TIKTOK ACCOUNT AFTER SAYING HE HAD ‘SERIOUS CONCERNS’ ABOUT CCP TIES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I think I could bring a lot of experience that I’ve gained — the experience I’ve taken from my subcommittee — as well as other experiences on the committee dealing in the [Indo-Pacific] area, as well as the Huaweis of the world and even things like TikTok," Gallego told Defense News in January 2023.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Despite past concerns, the Arizona congressman began to use the Chinese-linked app as he eyes the Democratic nomination for the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/us-regions/southwest/arizona" target="_blank"&gt;U.S. Senate seat&lt;/a&gt; in 2024.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/republicans-demand-fbi-dhs-update-congress-ongoing-tiktok-investigation" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;REPUBLICANS DEMAND FBI, DHS UPDATE CONGRESS ON ONGOING TIKTOK INVESTIGATION&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Just days ago, Gallego uploaded the first video to his verified TikTok account that showed a compilation of individuals holding up "Ruben Gallego for Arizona" signs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a statement to Fox News Digital, a spokesperson for Gallego's campaign said the candidate would keep fighting to protect privacy rights and hold China accountable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Ruben has a long record in Congress of holding the CCP accountable and will continue to fight to protect Arizonans’ security," the spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank"&gt;Many Republicans and some &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/elections/democrats" target="_blank"&gt;Democrats have expressed concerns&lt;/a&gt; over the CCP-tied platform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Vulnerable Sen. Sherrod Brown, D-Ohio, similarly expressed concerns over TikTok's ties to the Chinese Communist Party (CCP), but then months later &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/vulnerable-dem-senator-tiktok-account-serious-ccp-ties" target="_blank"&gt;created an account&lt;/a&gt; to promote his re-election campaign.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"We must protect Ohioans' personal information from the Chinese Communist Party," Brown told WTOL 11 when asked about his stance on the platform, suggesting the platform could potentially jeopardize the privacy of Ohioans.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/download" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;CLICK HERE TO GET THE FOX NEWS APP&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I have serious concerns with this company's ties to the Chinese government and will continue to work with members of both parties to look at how we can best protect Ohioans' privacy and our national security," the Senator said, just months before launching an account himself.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/gallego.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">45021cac-9b45-58f0-8e82-dec447f13419</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/world/world-regions/china</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/democratic-party</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/senate</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/national-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 12:27:55 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-bidens-sugar-bro-threatens-lawsuit-against-jonathan-turley</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-bidens-sugar-bro-threatens-lawsuit-against-jonathan-turley</guid>
      <title>Hunter Biden's 'sugar bro' threatens lawsuit against Jonathan Turley</title>
      <description>The &amp;quot;sugar brother&amp;quot; of President Joe Biden’s son, Hunter, is threatening legal action against criminal defense attorney Jonathan Turley.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The "sugar brother" of President &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/hunter-biden" target="_blank"&gt;Biden’s son, Hunter&lt;/a&gt;, is threatening legal action against criminal defense attorney and Fox News contributor Johnathan Turley, accusing him of defamation. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Kevin Morris, a Hollywood attorney and personal confidant to the younger Biden sat for a transcribed interview with the House Oversight Committee as part of House Republicans' &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/hunter-biden/hunter-biden-investigation-explained" target="_blank"&gt;sweeping probe into&lt;/a&gt; President Biden's family and its past foreign business dealings. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a 2022 column, Turley commented on Morris' position as a central figure in planning a "scorched Earth campaign" against "any investigation into the Bidens’ alleged multimillion-dollar influence-peddling schemes." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That plan, Turley noted, included "hitting critics . . . with possible defamation lawsuits." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fast-forward just over a year later — following his House committee interview in which he revealed he gave "massive' financial support to Hunter Biden" — Morris may be following through on his plan. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-bidens-sugar-brother-lawyer-confirms-he-still-holds-stake-chinese-state-backed-equity-fund"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HUNTER BIDEN'S 'SUGAR BROTHER' LAWYER CONFIRMS HE STILL HOLDS STAKE IN CHINESE STATE-BACKED EQUITY FUND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"On Wednesday, I received a letter from Bryan M. Sullivan, a partner at Early Sullivan Wright Gizer &amp;amp; McRae LLP, who is the lawyer of Kevin Morris (who is the lawyer for Hunter Biden). The letter warns that I could face a defamation action if I do not retract (or if I repeat) my criticism of Morris’s representational relationship with Hunter," Jonathan Turley wrote in his Friday column. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"In his letter, Sullivan attacks my reference to ethics rules as unworthy of a professor as well as 'blatantly misleading and just bad lawyering,'" said Turley. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"That tirade about my lack of knowledge and principles is followed by a demand for an immediate retraction and adds ‘if you repeat your baseless charges, you understand that accusing someone of violating the law is defamation &lt;i&gt;per se&lt;/i&gt;,’" he continued. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Turley stated that he "will not issue a retraction despite the threats of Morris and Sullivan." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instead, he published another column in the New York Post, repeating his "objections to Morris’s blurry representational claims."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/house-oversight-kevin-morris-gave-massive-financial-support-raising-campaign-finance-concerns"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEVIN MORRIS GAVE 'MASSIVE' FINANCIAL SUPPORT TO HUNTER BIDEN, RAISING CAMPAIGN FINANCE CONCERNS: COMER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"The effort in such threats is to silence or chill critics in their criticism of a wealthy, powerful public figure like Mr. Morris," Turley stated. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the Post column, Turley said that following his House testimony, the "question that lingered then, and now, is who is Kevin Morris."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"The Hollywood lawyer, producer &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/joe-biden" target="_blank"&gt;and Democratic donor&lt;/a&gt; has emerged as a major figure in the corruption scandal surrounding Hunter Biden. For years, some of us have complained that we are not sure what Morris was at any given moment," Turley stated. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-bidens-sugar-brother-goes-scorched-earth-on-comer-says-hes-confident-hunter-will-repay-loans"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HUNTER BIDEN'S 'SUGAR BROTHER' GOES SCORCHED EARTH ON COMER, SAYS HE'S 'CONFIDENT' HUNTER WILL REPAY LOANS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"What became clear in the deposition is that Morris does not appear certain himself," he added. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"He’s Hunter’s confidant, sugar brother, business partner, pitbull and his lawyer."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"That could prove his undoing . . . both for himself and his client," said Turley.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/GettyImages-1915184722.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">5af8fb89-9269-5a04-a470-1e3e1bd962d2</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/hunter-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/justice-department</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/white-house</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/congress</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 10:00:39 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-promises-shut-down-border-congress-approves-bill-gop-claims-incentivize-illegal-aliens</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-promises-shut-down-border-congress-approves-bill-gop-claims-incentivize-illegal-aliens</guid>
      <title>Biden promises to 'shut down' border if Congress approves bill GOP claims would 'incentivize illegal aliens'</title>
      <description>President Biden promised Friday to &amp;quot;shut down the border&amp;quot; with the &amp;quot;emergency authorities&amp;quot; he claims carve-outs of a Ukraine aid bill opposed by the GOP would confer him.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/joe-biden" target="_blank"&gt;President Biden&lt;/a&gt; is vowing to "shut down the border" if Congress passes the bipartisan immigration deal he claims would give him "emergency authority" necessary to stop the years-long surge of migrants.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Biden said in a Friday press release later published on social media that the border security measures, which are tied to a Ukraine aid package opposed by the GOP, would be "the toughest and fairest set of reforms to secure the border we've ever had as a country."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"For too long, we all know the border's been broken," the president said. "It's long past time to fix it."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-touts-potential-border-deal-senate-speaker-mike-johnson-says-bill-dead-on-arrival-house" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIDEN TOUTS POTENTIAL BORDER DEAL WITH SENATE AS SPEAKER MIKE JOHNSON SAYS BILL 'DEAD ON ARRIVAL' IN HOUSE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"What’s been negotiated would — if passed into law — be the toughest and fairest set of reforms to secure the border we’ve ever had in our country," Biden said. "It would give me, as president, a new emergency authority to shut down the border when it becomes overwhelmed. And if given that authority, I would use it the day I sign the bill into law."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/executive/white-house" target="_blank"&gt;White House statement&lt;/a&gt;, Biden urged lawmakers to provide funding to aid Ukraine that was requested in October, which would include funds for an additional 1,300 U.S. Border Patrol agents, 375 immigration judges, 1,600 asylum officers and more than 100 inspection machines to help prevent the smuggling of fentanyl into the United States. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It would also increase visas by 250,000 and bolster green card eligibility.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"For everyone demanding tougher border control, this is the way to do it," Biden said. "If you're serious about the border crisis, pass a bipartisan bill and I will sign it."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-urges-states-surge-national-guard-texas-abbott-standoff-with-biden-accelerates" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRUMP URGES STATES TO SURGE NATIONAL GUARD TO TEXAS AS ABBOTT STANDOFF WITH BIDEN ACCELERATES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hours earlier, House Speaker Mike Johnson wrote a letter to his colleagues in the Senate signaling the legislation addressing &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration/border-security" target="_blank"&gt;the border&lt;/a&gt; and aid to Ukraine has no future in the House if Republicans there feel it doesn't do enough to address the record numbers of illegal immigrants crossing into the United States.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I wanted to provide a brief update regarding the supplemental and the border, since the Senate appears unable to reach any agreement. If rumors about the contents of the draft proposal are true, it would have been dead on arrival in the House anyway," Johnson wrote. "Many of our constituents have asked an important question: ‘What is the point of negotiating new laws with an administration that will not enforce the laws already on the books?’"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Johnson suggested that the GOP was not interested in negotiating the bill because Biden has failed to enforce illegal immigration laws already on the books.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/border-battle-lines-dems-biden-seize-control-texas-national-guard-gop-allies-back-abbott" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BORDER BATTLE LINES: DEMS CALL ON BIDEN TO SEIZE CONTROL OF TEXAS NATIONAL GUARD, AS GOP ALLIES BACK ABBOTT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I am emphasizing again today that House Republicans will vigorously oppose any new policy proposal from the White House or Senate that would further incentivize illegal aliens to break our laws," Johnson said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Biden's claim that the bill was necessary to confer him with the authority to close the border received notable pushback from conservatives, who pointed to a variety of powers currently at his disposal to stop the hundreds of thousands of migrants pouring into the U.S.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"No laws need to be passed," billionaire &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/elon-musk" target="_blank"&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;, who owns the X social media platform, responded to Biden's announcement. "All that is needed is an executive order to require proof before granting an asylum hearing. That is how it used to be."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Just this week, Border Patrol agents near El Paso, Texas, &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/border-patrol-catches-40-illegal-migrants-stuffed-several-vehicles" target="_blank"&gt;caught 40 migrants&lt;/a&gt; involved in two human smuggling operations as the border hit its highest rate of migrant encounters last month, blowing away previous statistics. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.is/o/O6SNZ/https://www.foxnews.com/download" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLICK HERE TO GET THE FOX NEWS APP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sources with &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration" target="_blank"&gt;Customs and Border Protection&lt;/a&gt; told Fox News Digital that migrant encounters hit a staggering 300,000 incidents in the last month of 2023, reaching a level thought unimaginable just years ago.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Between Dec. 1 and 31, more than 302,000 migrants were documented attempting to cross the U.S. southern border. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is the highest total for a single month ever recorded. It is also the first time migrant encounters have exceeded 300,000. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fox News Digital's Louis Casiano and Brie Stimson contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2023/01/931/523/Politics-Biden-El-Paso-Border-visit.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">2aa62d01-89f8-5043-b610-b8cdb28983b0</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/illegal-immigrants</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/world/migrant-caravan</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/border-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/topic/border-wall</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/mexico</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/presidential-primaries</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 07:37:15 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/crisis-northwest-voters-beyond-turning-point-decades-progressive-politics</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/crisis-northwest-voters-beyond-turning-point-decades-progressive-politics</guid>
      <title>Crisis in the Northwest: Are voters 'beyond a turning point' after decades of progressive politics?</title>
      <description>Both sides of the aisle agree Oregon is in crisis — homelessness, drug use and livability are the major concerns — but can they effectively reverse course?</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is the first story in a series about the addiction and homelessness crises plaguing Oregon.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;SALEM, Ore. – It was a quiet morning, aside from the man shouting incoherently behind the Oregon State Capitol. He paced back and forth, occasionally flailing his arms, and seemed unbothered by the January drizzle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Inside the building, lawmakers filtered in and out of meetings, trying to figure out how best to address homelessness, mental health and addiction in the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/state-and-local" target="_blank"&gt;upcoming legislative session&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"We have a crisis on our hands and that’s easy to see," Republican Rep. Lucetta Elmer told Fox News Digital. "Something has to change. And Oregonians are asking for that change."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/fentanyl-nexus-portland-polices-bike-squad-faces-explosion-open-air-drug-use" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘FENTANYL NEXUS’: PORTLAND POLICE’S BIKE SQUAD FACES ‘EXPLOSION’ OF OPEN-AIR DRUG USE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A man with curly brown hair cascading out from under a beanie struggled to light a flame under his meth pipe on a sidewalk in Portland's Chinatown neighborhood. He tried to block the breeze with swollen, pink fingers, but the wind was too strong. So he tented a wool blanket over his head. He emerged a moment later along with a dense cloud of smoke.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tara Faul snapped the portrait.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Really sad,"&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;she said afterward, asked how it feels to document the moment. Before she could continue, another man started shouting obscenities from underneath a Portland Timbers blanket. "And sometimes scary," she said. "We should probably move."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Faul grew up on the Oregon Coast and bought a house in Portland in 2018. She loved everything about the city — the culture, the food and especially the weather.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But in 2020, she felt a growing sense of despair. She could &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/riots-caused-generational-damage-police-discourse-union-president-sees-improvement-city" target="_blank"&gt;hear riots&lt;/a&gt; from her home some nights. She had to call her kids in from the yard when a man wandered by with a machete. A nearby house was shot up so many times it became difficult to distinguish the new bullet holes from the old.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"You couldn’t go out the door without having something crazy happen to you," she said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What she heard on the news and social media did not match what she witnessed in real life.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So she grabbed a camera and started documenting what she saw, trying to put an artistic flair on the piles of garbage that had become prevalent in the city. She chats with drug users and homeless people as she snaps their portraits.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/digital-originals" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;WATCH MORE FOX NEWS DIGITAL ORIGINALS HERE&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lately, her most famous pictures have been of human excrement splattered on walls and sidewalks as the city’s homeless community faces a surge in the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/portland-health-officials-report-waste-borne-illness-rampant-among-citys-homeless" target="_blank"&gt;waste-borne illness&lt;/a&gt; Shigella.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Those who deride the "liberal sh--hole of Portland" on X often don’t know what to make of Faul’s appearance. The homeschooling mother of four’s short hair, piercings and tattered band T-shirts hardly scream "Trump voter" and instead regularly earn her obscenity-laden accusations that she "voted for this" and deserves "every bit of what happens to you."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I get it," she said. "I look like I voted for the poop."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pioneers flocked to the land of "milk and honey" in the 1800s, seeking fertile soil and bountiful agriculture. Over time, Oregon became famous for its breathtaking natural scenery — Willamette Valley residents cherish being a mere hour from the coast and an hour from the Cascades — timber, craft breweries and coffee shops.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That picturesque scene has become tarnished.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Graffiti, tents and trash litter sidewalks and roadsides as Oregon contends with one of the highest rates of homelessness. &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/health/fourth-wave-fentanyl-overdose-deaths-gripped-nation-experts-say-norm-not-exception" target="_blank"&gt;Fentanyl deaths&lt;/a&gt; surged more than 67% last year, the biggest increase in the nation, according to an analysis by the organization Families Against Fentanyl.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/crime" target="_blank"&gt;Violent crime&lt;/a&gt; rates spiked 16.6% in the state from 2019 to 2022, according to FBI data, though Oregon remains safer than the national average. Car thefts surged nearly 50%, with 551.5 thefts reported for every 100,000 people in Oregon in 2022, compared to the national average of 282.7.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Only 29% of Oregonians polled by DHM Research last year said the state is headed in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"We are on the absolute wrong track," Elmer said. "We are in a health crisis because of the rampant drug use. We are in a justice crisis because we're not able to deal with people who are breaking the law. We’re in a generational crisis."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/open-air-drug-use-overdoses-push-democrats-introduce-overhaul-first-nation-decriminalization-law" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPEN-AIR DRUG USE, OVERDOSES PUSH DEMOCRATS TO INTRODUCE OVERHAUL OF FIRST-IN-THE-NATION DECRIMINALIZATION LAW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Online, more contemptuous conservatives rejoice in Oregon’s current downturn, pointing to it as an example of failed progressive policies. A Republican hasn't governed Oregon since the 1980s. Democrats dominate both chambers of the legislature. Voters brought this upon themselves and any &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/secede-oregon-greater-idaho-ballot-two-conservative-counties" target="_blank"&gt;lingering conservatives&lt;/a&gt; should flee now, go the predictable comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I wish [Oregon] wasn't always easy to kind of dunk on," Clackamas County &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/focus-merit-oregon-county-axes-diversity-office-cost-nearly-1-million-year" target="_blank"&gt;Commissioner Ben West&lt;/a&gt; said. "Much of what has happened is that there's a lack of balance in Oregon … Politics is downstream from culture, and elections have consequences."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Both parties have signaled a desire to roll back the state’s landmark &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/enormous-mistake-business-leaders-residents-fed-blue-state-drug-laws-issue-2024-ultimatum" target="_blank"&gt;drug decriminalization law&lt;/a&gt; during the February legislative session. A Democratic lawmaker is considering bringing back involuntary commitment. City leaders — including those in Portland — hope the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/opinion/supreme-court-case-could-help-cities-clean-up-homelessness" target="_blank"&gt;Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; will give them the power to restrict homeless people camping on public property.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I think the voters and the residents are beyond a turning point," West, a sixth-generation Oregonian, said of the state's political mood. But he's not confident lawmakers will do more than "nibble around the edges" of reform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Faul counts herself among the 56% of Portlanders who said they would leave the city in a recent poll. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"It would make me sad because I love this place, and I used to tell everybody that it was the best city in the country," she said. "I had a ton of pride in Portland."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;She has done plenty of Zillow scrolling and research on potential places to move, but said high interest rates and housing costs have made it "not a good world to try to move around in."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"So I'm sure a lot of people just feel trapped," she said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/judge-blocks-americas-extreme-gun-control-law-blue-state-plans-appeal" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JUDGE BLOCKS AMERICA'S 'MOST EXTREME' GUN CONTROL LAW, BUT BLUE STATE PLANS TO APPEAL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oregon’s population dipped in 2022 for the first time in nearly 40 years and, according to recent Census Bureau estimates, the downturn continued in 2023. High earners left Multnomah County in droves between 2020 and 2021, taking more than $1 billion in tax revenue with them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"That's a sign of how unique and critical this moment is," Portland City Commissioner and mayoral candidate Mingus Mapps said. "We have to get this right, and the things that we need to be focusing in on are houselessness, public safety and economic vitality."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oregon's problems are most prominently displayed in Portland. Open-air drug use, block after block of RVs and tents, &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/choose-not-live-fear-portland-coffee-shop-bounces-back-targeted-attack-police-event" target="_blank"&gt;vandalism&lt;/a&gt; and office buildings that still haven't refilled after the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"There's no question Portland's been through a rough patch," Mayor Ted Wheeler said. "We have experienced an unprecedented number of simultaneous worst-case scenario crises."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That's why &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/oregon-gov-tina-kotek-directs-state-police-crack-down-fentanyl-distribution-hold-sellers-accountable" target="_blank"&gt;Gov. Tina Kotek&lt;/a&gt; made restoring the City of Roses a top priority after taking office last year, sending in state troopers to help crack down on fentanyl dealing. She recently unveiled a bundle of proposals she hopes will encourage economic activity in the city, including a sweeping effort to clear graffiti and garbage, and a push to bring down the remaining 2020-era plywood — the latter of which received chuckles and eye rolls from locals who have grown accustomed to the sight of boarded-up windows.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Portland's city council welcomes Kotek’s vision. &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/portland" target="_blank"&gt;Downtown Portland&lt;/a&gt; is the "economic engine of both the city" and the state, Mapps said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"If downtown Portland goes down, the entire state of Oregon goes down," he said. "We cannot allow that to happen."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As local leaders await the outcome of Oregon's special legislative session, set to begin Feb. 5, West said Oregon and the northwest are "absolutely worth fighting for."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"There's still a lot of good here and a lot of great people across this entire state," he said. "Great businesses and people that do work hard to help make Oregon better. And so I want to fight with those people."&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/crisis-in-the-nw-1-thumbnail.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">128f6f7f-ac9a-534e-8c0b-e61ed5c38243</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/digital-originals</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/west/oregon</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/portland</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/state-and-local</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/topic/homeless-crisis</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/crime/drugs</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/health/mental-health/drug-and-substance-abuse</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/health/mental-health/addiction</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/crime</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 07:30:46 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/experts-turley-painter-say-texas-shaky-legal-ground-border-razor-wire-fight</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/experts-turley-painter-say-texas-shaky-legal-ground-border-razor-wire-fight</guid>
      <title>Experts Turley, Painter say Texas on shaky legal ground in border razor-wire fight</title>
      <description>Legal experts weighed in on the battle between Texas and the Biden administration over the southern border that reached new temperatures this week.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Texas is battling &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/joe-biden" target="_blank"&gt;President Biden&lt;/a&gt; in the courts and on the ground over illegal immigration at the southern border.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/us-regions/southwest/texas" target="_blank"&gt;Lone Star State&lt;/a&gt; defied the Biden administration this week after the Supreme Court granted an emergency appeal to allow federal officials to cut razor wire Gov. Greg Abbott ordered to be installed at the southern border.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Republican governor responded to &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/entertainment/events/in-court" target="_blank"&gt;the court&lt;/a&gt; by posting pictures of the Texas National Guard bolstering the border, declaring on Wednesday that Texas has a right to "self-defense" from a migrant "invasion" at the southern border.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/border-battle-lines-dems-biden-seize-control-texas-national-guard-gop-allies-back-abbott" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BORDER BATTLE LINES: DEMS CALL ON BIDEN TO SEIZE CONTROL OF TEXAS NATIONAL GUARD, AS GOP ALLIES BACK ABBOTT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Abbott's move led to Democrats' calls for Biden to take control of the Texas National Guard.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;George Washington University law professor and Fox News contributor Jonathan Turley told Fox News Digital that while "many agree" with Texas' objections and "oppose" how the Biden administration is handling &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration/border-security" target="_blank"&gt;the border&lt;/a&gt;, the federal government now has a "sufficient basis" to "move forward."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"After the Supreme Court lifted the injunction on the removal, Texas is without legal cause to prevent access by the federal agents," Turley said. "Texas would need to secure another injunction, but it is hard to imagine what that basis would be in light of the decision of the court.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"It can resume litigation, but legally it could be ‘all hat, no cattle’ in defying the federal orders," Turley added.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Texas can seek an alternative means to secure the border. However, it is unlikely to get much support in the federal courts."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;University of Minnesota &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/executive/law" target="_blank"&gt;law professor Richard Painter&lt;/a&gt; told Fox News Digital the issue boils down to federal supremacy doctrine and that "the general problem here is we have no consistent arguments from anybody about who's in charge of immigration law."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Whether it's the federal government only, the federal government and the states … and do we have combined control or a partnership or do we have just the federal government?" Painter wondered.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Painter said "neither party is being completely consistent here," criticizing the Democrats for supporting sanctuary city policies and adding it is "unacceptable" that there are cities that will not enforce immigration law.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Additionally, Painter said Texas is going against Biden on the issue because "they believe that Biden is not adequately protecting the United States against illegal immigration, even though that's really the Biden administration's job."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"And so Texas now is taking advantage of some ambiguity in the law, to do what it wants to do itself to address the problem they feel that President Biden is not adequately addressing," Painter said. "And states have the right to do that unless they're clearly preempted by federal law."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Abbott issued a lengthy statement Wednesday, saying the federal government broke the compact between the U.S. and the individual states.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"The executive branch of the United States has a constitutional duty to enforce federal laws protecting states, including immigration laws on the books right now," &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/greg-abbott" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Abbott said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. "President Biden has refused to enforce those laws and has even violated them."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Abbott is fighting multiple legal battles with the Biden administration, which has threatened legal action over Texas’ seizure of Shelby Park near Eagle Pass. Texas has also filed lawsuits against the administration, which cut razor wire set up by the state on the Rio Grande to prevent migrants from illegally crossing into Texas.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fox News Digital's Adam Shaw and Greg Wehner contributed reporting.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2023/09/931/523/GettyImages-1693680773.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">befa36a0-d386-579a-a477-dc584c8da9ed</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/newsedge/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/house-of-representatives/republicans</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/house-of-representatives/democrats</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/southwest/texas</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/border-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 04:00:51 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/energy-developer-delivers-major-blow-blue-states-climate-agenda</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/energy-developer-delivers-major-blow-blue-states-climate-agenda</guid>
      <title>Energy developer delivers major blow to blue state's climate agenda by canceling offshore wind contracts</title>
      <description>A major energy developer is pulling out of contracts it entered into with the State of Maryland to build two large offshore wind farms in a blow to Democrats&amp;apos; green energy goals.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Multinational energy developer Orsted unexpectedly withdrew from agreements &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/us-regions/northeast/maryland" target="_blank"&gt;with the State of Maryland&lt;/a&gt; to develop two offshore wind projects, citing worsening economic conditions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Orsted announced that it had pulled out of orders which the &lt;a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/politics/grid-operator-sounds-alarm-coal-plant-shutdown-threatens-power-millions" target="_blank"&gt;Maryland Public Service Commission (PSC)&lt;/a&gt; issued years ago greenlighting the so-called Skipjack Wind 1 and Skipjack Wind 2 projects, and selecting the projects for a 20-year Offshore Renewable Energy Credit (OREC). Maryland Democrats repeatedly pointed to the Skipjack Wind development as a key part of the state's aggressive decarbonization agenda.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Today’s announcement affirms our commitment to developing value creating projects and represents an opportunity to reposition Skipjack Wind, located in a strategically valuable federal lease area and with a state that is highly supportive of offshore wind, for future offtake opportunities," David Hardy, Orsted's group executive vice president and CEO of its Americas division, said Thursday in a statement.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"As we explore the best path forward for Skipjack Wind, we anticipate several opportunities and will evaluate each as it becomes available," he continued.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/top-officials-warned-biden-admin-dangers-wind-energy-projects-pose-fishing-industry-letter-shows" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;TOP OFFICIALS WARNED BIDEN ADMIN ABOUT DANGERS WIND ENERGY PROJECTS POSE TO FISHING INDUSTRY, LETTER SHOWS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hardy added that the decision was made in light of "challenging economic circumstances." According to Orsted, the ORECs set forth under the company's agreement with the state are no longer commercially viable as a result of market conditions, including inflation, high interest rates and supply chain constraints.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The developer, though, hasn't canceled the project altogether and will continue to advance its development and permitting, additionally submitting an up-to-date Construction and Operations Plan to the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/republicans-accelerate-investigation-biden-cabinet-official-ties-left-wing-eco-group" target="_blank"&gt;U.S. Department of the Interior&lt;/a&gt;. Orsted said the move allows it to reposition Skipjack Wind for future offtake opportunities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/major-wind-project-dependent-biden-admin-waiving-taxpayer-safeguard-internal-docs" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MAJOR WIND PROJECT WAS DEPENDENT ON BIDEN ADMIN WAIVING TAXPAYER SAFEGUARD: INTERNAL DOCS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Governor Moore is disappointed by the news of Ørsted’s repositioning of the Skipjack Wind project, an effort that has the capacity to impact the lives of so many Marylanders," Carter Elliott, a spokesperson for Democratic Maryland Gov. Wes Moore, told Fox News Digital in an email. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"However, he will continue to work with legislators, Maryland’s federal partners, offshore wind developers, and advocates that see Maryland’s potential in order to build a system to help Maryland reach the state’s goal of 100% clean energy by 2035," Elliott added. "If this is going to be Maryland's decade, we must continue to push forward to reach the state's ambitious climate goals, and the governor is as committed as ever to doing just that."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Overall, the joint project was set to be constructed roughly 20 miles off the coast of the Delmarva Peninsula near the Maryland-Delaware border and be commissioned by 2026. The two projects were projected to have a total capacity of 966 megawatts, enough to &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/energy-developer-axing-key-coal-power-plants-meet-eco-goals-jeopardizing-power-millions" target="_blank"&gt;power hundreds of thousands of homes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The announcement, though, leaves Maryland with just two proposed offshore wind projects: the 300-megawatt MarWin project and the 800-megawatt Momentum Wind project, which are both set to be built off the coast of Ocean City, Maryland, and are being developed by the Baltimore firm US Wind.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-admin-makes-stunning-admission-climate-agenda-leaked-internal-memo" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;BIDEN ADMIN MAKES STUNNING ADMISSION ON CLIMATE AGENDA IN LEAKED INTERNAL MEMO&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Yesterday’s news from Orsted is disappointing — the Skipjack project was an important component in advancing Maryland’s clean energy goals," Maryland PSC Chairman Frederick Hoover said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"However, the Commission remains optimistic about the future of the offshore wind industry in Maryland, and would note that the US Wind project continues to move through the federal approval process," Hoover added.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Republican Maryland Rep. Andy Harris, though, cheered Orsted's decision, which came days after he and other lawmakers held a public hearing calling for the end of offshore wind industrialization in Maryland.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"This is welcome news for the many watermen and residents in Maryland who have made it clear they don’t want foreign-owned offshore wind companies industrializing their coasts," he said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/dc-green-lights-aggressive-electric-vehicle-mandate-critics-sounding-alarm-high-consumer-costs" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;DC GREENLIGHTS AGGRESSIVE ELECTRIC VEHICLE MANDATE DESPITE CRITICS SOUNDING ALARM ON HIGH CONSUMER COSTS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Skipjack Wind projects are among several that have faced headwinds amid economic uncertainty. In November, Orsted &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/developer-axes-two-major-offshore-wind-projects-blow-bidens-green-energy-goals" target="_blank"&gt;announced that it had canceled&lt;/a&gt; its Ocean Wind 1 and Ocean Wind 2 twin projects off the coast of New Jersey, and, earlier this month, energy firms Equinor and BP pulled out of a contract with the State of New York for their Empire Wind 2 project.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The actions threaten to crush green energy goals set by Democratic-led states and the Biden administration. &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-admin-rushing-industrialize-us-oceans-stop-climate-change-environmental-wrecking-ball" target="_blank"&gt;President Biden has set goals&lt;/a&gt; of deploying 30 gigawatts of offshore wind energy by 2030, the most ambitious goal of its kind worldwide, and completely decarbonizing the power grid by 2035.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"These projects are unaffordable, they are ridiculous," Dave Stevenson, the director of the Center for Energy Competitiveness at Delaware-based free market think tank Caesar Rodney Institute, told Fox News Digital in an interview. "The question really does become, in light of these disruptions and price increases, why shouldn't we expect more?"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"It just gets worse and worse and worse," said Stevenson, who is also the president of the American Coalition for Ocean Protection. "When you have bad news like this repetitively, it's a clear message that this is not ready for primetime. These projects should just stop. Let's take another path as to how we're going to generate electricity down the road."&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/Maryland-offshore-wind.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">66443f90-d6b3-59c7-aa99-effa69f2b955</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/economy/green-economy</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/energy</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/columns/energy-in-america</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/northeast/maryland</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/white-house</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 04:00:25 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/schumer-aligned-super-pac-meddling-gop-primary-key-senate-race</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/schumer-aligned-super-pac-meddling-gop-primary-key-senate-race</guid>
      <title>Schumer-aligned super PAC meddling in GOP primary of key Senate race: 'Terrified of conservative outsider'</title>
      <description>Democrats are buying ads boosting GOP Rep. Matt Rosendale ahead of his expected Senate bid, a campaign tactic dug up from the 2022 midterms.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A Democratic super PAC, which is aligned with Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer of New York, is behind a shadowy group buying ads boosting potential &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/elections/republicans" target="_blank"&gt;Republican Senate&lt;/a&gt; candidate Rep. Matt Rosendale, who is mulling a Senate bid to challenge conservative firebrand Tim Sheehy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 2022, Democrats spent more than $40 million to boost Republican candidates ahead of their state's primary in the hopes that they would win and be the more beatable candidate in the general election - and in some cases the strategy &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/clean-sweep-democrats-cash-in-boosting-pro-trump-candidates-republican-primaries" target="_blank"&gt;actually proved successful&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As Democrats grip onto their slim Senate majority in 2024, they are honing in on the Montana Senate race, which sees Sen. Jon Tester, D-Mont., attempting to hold onto the only statewide blue seat in the state. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A Democrat-tied Facebook page, under the name "Treasure State Truths," has already bought several ads in the Montana Senate primary race - bashing Sheehy, while simultaneously boosting his potential GOP opponent Rep. Matt Rosendale, R-Mont.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/former-navy-seal-major-fundraising-haul-bid-unseat-vulnerable-dem-senator" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;FORMER NAVY SEAL HAS MAJOR FUNDRAISING HAUL IN BID TO UNSEAT VULNERABLE&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Their page shows ads running from December 13 that attempt to paint Navy SEAL Sheehy in a negative light by writing that voters "can't trust" him, while other ads link to articles praising Rosendale for his pro-life advocacy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The group is managed by Gambit Strategies LLC, a Washington D.C. based digital marketing group that works to "efficiently persuade" voters in favor of the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/elections/democrats" target="_blank"&gt;Democrat party&lt;/a&gt; and Democrat candidates nationwide. According to the Federal Election Commission (FEC) website, the firm received millions of dollars from Biden's re-election campaign last year in addition to six-figure payments from several Democratic campaigns dating back to 2021.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/conservative-firebrand-praises-matt-rosendale-ahead-potential-senate-bid-shock-system" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;CONSERVATIVE FIREBRAND PRAISES MATT ROSENDALE AHEAD OF POTENTIAL SENATE BID: ‘SHOCK TO THE SYSTEM’&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"No one has overseen more spending on digital persuasion, mobilization, and issue advocacy programs than us in the Democratic Party since 2016," the Gambit Strategies homepage reads. "That’s why we specialize in running digital campaigns that effectively and efficiently persuade and mobilize your audience by defining candidates, causes, and issues."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another mysterious group, the Last Best Place PAC, has already spent millions of dollars on several ads against Sheehy, a signal his rising candidacy could be detrimental to the Democrats' majority if he becomes the GOP nominee in 2024.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Senate Majority PAC, which is aligned with Schumer, confirmed to Fox News Digital that they are the group behind the Last Best Place PAC targeting Sheehy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to AdImpact, an ad intel website, Last Best Place PAC is planning to spend over $5 million attacking Sheehy in the race to unseat Tester.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"This confirmed what we knew all along that Chuck Schumer is spending millions of dollars interfering in Montana’s election to tear down combat veteran Tim Sheehy because they know he’s a strong conservative who will win in November, and they want the weakest candidate in this race who will give Two-Faced Tester another victory in November," a spokesperson for Sheehy told Fox News Digital. "The career politicians back in DC are terrified of conservative outsider Tim Sheehy because he’s going to stand shoulder to shoulder with President Trump to drain the swamp, save our country, and put America and Montana First!"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sheehy has gained national attention after his campaign gained various prominent endorsements, including from all of Montana's top leadership - Sen. Steve Daines, Rep. Ryan Zinke, R-Mont., and Gov. Greg Gianforte, R-Mont.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The stakes were recently heightened last month after the Cook Report, an "independent, non-partisan" election forecaster, &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/toughest-uphill-climb-forecaster-shift-toward-gop-2024-senate-race" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;shifted the race&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from "Lean Democrat" to "Toss-Up."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rosendale has not officially launched a bid for &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/senate" target="_blank"&gt;the Senate&lt;/a&gt;, but has confirmed several times that he is highly considering jumping into the race.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/elections" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Get the latest updates from the 2024 campaign trail, exclusive interviews and more at our Fox News Digital election hub.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2023/08/931/523/Sheehy-Tester.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">df6142c7-1dcc-5b2b-b1d0-7bf1b2a42b27</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/republicans</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/democratic-party</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/senate</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/campaigning</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/2023/primary-results</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 04:00:22 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/ex-fbi-officials-warn-congress-new-imminent-border-threat-the-country-invaded</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/ex-fbi-officials-warn-congress-new-imminent-border-threat-the-country-invaded</guid>
      <title>Ex-FBI officials warn Congress of 'new and imminent' border danger: 'The country has been invaded'</title>
      <description>A coalition of former FBI officials is warning about a new threat at the southern border due to the ongoing migrant crisis and is calling on leaders to act.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A coalition of &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/tech/topics/fbi" target="_blank"&gt;former FBI officials&lt;/a&gt; has issued a warning about a "new and imminent danger" for the U.S. at the southern border, suggesting the country has "been invaded" by military-age foreign nationals.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a letter sent last week to congressional leaders in the House and Senate, the retired officials "express our concern about a current, specific threat that may be one of the most pernicious ever to menace the United States."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The letter warns "the United States is facing a new and imminent danger" and highlights what the officials say is a threat of an invasion at the southern border, where there were over 302,000 migrant encounters in December after a record fiscal 2023 in which there were 2.4 million migrant encounters.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"In its modern history, the U.S. has never suffered an invasion of the homeland and, yet, one is unfolding now," they say. "Military aged men from across the globe, many from countries or regions not friendly to the United States, are landing in waves on our soil by the thousands — not by splashing ashore from a ship or parachuting from a plane but rather by foot across a border that has been accurately advertised around the world as largely unprotected with ready access granted."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/migrant-crisis-broke-new-record-in-december-with-302k-encounters-officials-confirm" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MIGRANT CRISIS BROKE NEW RECORD IN DECEMBER WITH 302K ENCOUNTERS, OFFICIALS CONFIRM &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The ten officials include former FBI assistant directors Kevin Brock and Chris Swecker, former Terrorist Screening Center Director Timothy Healy and former acting Customs and Border Protection Commissioner Mark Morgan, who is also a former FBI superintendent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The lawmakers note the releases of migrants into the country in large numbers, although federal officials have repeatedly claimed that migrants are only released after going through a multi-layered vetting process and biographical and biometric vetting. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;They also note numbers of gotaways, which are estimated to have exceeded 800,000 last fiscal year, and encounters of those on the FBI’s terror watch list. &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/fbi-director-wray-says-border-gotaways-a-source-of-great-concern-for-agency" target="_blank"&gt;FBI Director Christopher Wray&lt;/a&gt; has also expressed concern about who is evading Border Patrol. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Biden administration has, however, also said it has greater awareness of the border now and that gotaways are a decades-old problem for the country.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"With the investments that this Congress has made in the Border Patrol, CBP as a whole, we have greater situational awareness now than I’ve ever had," &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration/border-security" target="_blank"&gt;Border Patrol Chief&lt;/a&gt; Raul Ortiz said in March last year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The former officials express concern, particularly in light of the Oct. 7 Hamas attack on Israel.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/border-patrol-has-no-plans-remove-razor-wire-set-up-texas-amid-feud-biden-admin" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;BORDER PATROL HAS ‘NO PLANS’ TO REMOVE RAZOR WIRE SET UP BY TEXAS AMID FEUD WITH BIDEN ADMIN&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"It is stark to say so, but having a large number of young males now within our borders who could begin attacking gatherings of unarmed citizens, in imitation of 10/7 and at the behest of a foreign terror group, must be considered a distinct possibility," they wrote. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"We would be remiss not to call out this potentially grave threat in the most direct terms. The warning lights are blinking."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;They warn that some of the men arriving to the border are from terror-linked areas as well as geopolitical foes like &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/world/world-regions/china" target="_blank"&gt;China and Russia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"For these reasons, elements of this recent surge are likely no accident or coincidence. These men are potential operators in what appears to be an accelerated and strategic penetration, a soft invasion, designed to gain internal access to a country that cannot be invaded militarily in order to inflict catastrophic damage if and when enemies deem it necessary," they say.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/congress" target="_blank"&gt;They encourage Congress&lt;/a&gt; and other federal leaders to take action and pay more attention to the threat.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/5000-illegal-immigrants-released-every-day-us-admin-officials-privately-tell-lawmakers" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;5,000 ILLEGAL IMMIGRANTS RELEASED EVERY DAY INTO US, ADMIN OFFICIALS PRIVATELY TELL LAWMAKERS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"The country has been invaded, an invasion that will continue as long as the nation’s enemies perceive it will be tolerated," they say.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The letter was written at a time when border security is a top political issue. Republicans have blamed the migrant crisis on &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/joe-biden" target="_blank"&gt;Biden-era policies&lt;/a&gt; and the reversal of Trump-era policies. The administration says it needs more funding and reforms to fix a "broken" system and deal with a hemisphere-wide crisis. DHS has also pointed to an increase in returns of illegal immigrants, including more since May than in the entirety of fiscal 2019.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lawmakers are debating a supplemental spending bill that includes &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/senate-border-bill-allow-5000-migrants-day-before-title-42-limit-starts" target="_blank"&gt;$14 billion for border funding&lt;/a&gt; for staffing, processing, removals and aid to cities and organizations. Republicans, however, want to see tightened asylum restrictions and fewer parole releases.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2023/09/931/523/venezuela.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">df9ee1bd-8a43-5812-894c-bb80ed6c7cf5</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/border-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/homeland-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/illegal-immigrants</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/tech/topics/fbi</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/mexico</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 04:00:04 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/haley-grassroots-fundraising-soars-top-dollar-donor-wants-see-path-victory</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/haley-grassroots-fundraising-soars-top-dollar-donor-wants-see-path-victory</guid>
      <title>Haley's grassroots fundraising soars, but a top-dollar liberal donor wants to see 'path to victory'</title>
      <description>Nikki Haley will need to demonstrate that there is a “new potential path to victory&amp;quot; over former President Donald Trump for the GOP nomination before she gets any more donations from billionaire Reid Hoffman.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/nikki-haley" target="_blank"&gt;Nikki Haley&lt;/a&gt; is enjoying a surge in small dollar, grassroots fundraising.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But following her 11-point loss to former President Donald Trump in &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/us-regions/northeast/new-hampshire" target="_blank"&gt;New Hampshire's primary&lt;/a&gt; — which was seen by political pundits as her best shot at slowing down Trump's push for the GOP nomination — liberal megadonor and LinkedIn cofounder Reid Hoffman appears to be one of the first wealthy donors who's apparently heading for an exit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A top adviser to the megadonor told Fox News that a "new potential path to victory" would be needed to appear before sending any further contributions to Haley.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the 24 hours after her runner-up finish to &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/donald-trump" target="_blank"&gt;Trump&lt;/a&gt; in Tuesday's Republican presidential primary in New Hampshire, the former two-term South Carolina governor who later served as U.N. ambassador in the Trump administration hauled in $1 million in grassroots online donations.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As Fox News first reported on Thursday, Haley raked in another $1 million after she responded on social media to a warning Trump directed to GOP donors to stop contributing to his remaining major rival for the 2024 Republican nomination. Hours later, the campaign touted that total 48-hour haul had reached $2.6 million.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Haley is campaigning this weekend in her home state, which on Feb. 24 will hold the next major primary on the Republican nominating calendar. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/haley-campaign-cash-trump-warned-donors-barred-maga" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HALEY RAKES IN CAMPAIGN CASH AFTER TRUMP WARNS TOP DOLLAR DONORS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;She will then head to New York City early next week to meet with some top &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/elections/republicans" target="_blank"&gt;Republican donors&lt;/a&gt; as she aims to replenish her campaign coffers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sources in Haley's political orbit told Fox News that &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/elections/fundraising" target="_blank"&gt;a fundraiser&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday co-hosted by billionaires Leonard Stern, Cliff Asness, Stanley Druckenmiller, Ken Langone and Henry Kravis remains on her schedule.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-aligned-super-pac-sees-surge-fundraising" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRUMP ALIGNED SUPER PAC SEES SURGE IN FUNDRAISING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is one of roughly 10 fundraisers with major Republican donors on Haley's itinerary over the next couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/haley-lives-to-fight-another-day-against-trump-but-faces-challenging-road-ahead-gop-presidential-race" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HALEY LIVES TO FIGHT ANOTHER DAY, BUT FACES A ‘CHALLENGING’ ROAD AHEAD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hoffman, a supporter of &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/joe-biden" target="_blank"&gt;President Biden&lt;/a&gt; who contributed over three-quarters of a million dollars last year to the Biden Victory Fund, gave a quarter of a million dollars last month to SFA Fund, Inc, the Haley-aligned super PAC.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Prior to the primaries, we made an investment in Governor Haley because we saw that her performance in New Hampshire might give her a path to defeating Donald Trump," Hoffman’s political philanthropy adviser Dmitri Mehlhorn said in a statement to Fox News.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the New Hampshire primary now in the rearview mirror, Mehlhorn said that "it is still possible that Governor Haley will be able to persuade voters that Trump is no longer stable and cannot carry their banner into the fall campaign."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But he emphasized that "before recommending another investment at this later stage in the process, however, I would need to see a new potential path to victory given that she did not win New Hampshire."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"The only way I can see a path happening is if Trump has a ‘senior moment,' and she's able to exploit it to persuade GOP voters that he's lost it," Mehlhorn added.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hoffman has long been a vocal critic of the former president. Mehlhorn said that "if it becomes clear that the GOP has decided to nominate Trump, we have no choice but to turn our attention to defeating Trump in the general election."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump and his allies have repeatedly blasted Haley since Hoffman's contribution to her super PAC grabbed headlines in early December.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/elections" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Get the latest updates from the 2024 campaign trail, exclusive interviews and more at our Fox News Digital election hub.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/Nikki-Haley-North-Charleston-SC-Jan.-24-2024.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">d03ccc26-35ed-591e-a50b-535ec9dcd1c6</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/republican-convention</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/presidential-primaries</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/fundraising</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/nikki-haley</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/donald-trump</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/northeast/new-hampshire</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 04:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/white-house-says-deeply-troubled-alabamas-execution-man-using-nitrogen-gas</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/white-house-says-deeply-troubled-alabamas-execution-man-using-nitrogen-gas</guid>
      <title>White House says it is 'deeply troubled' by Alabama's execution of man using nitrogen gas</title>
      <description>White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said the White House is &amp;quot;deeply troubled&amp;quot; by Alabama&amp;apos;s experimental execution in which a man was put to death by nitrogen gas.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said Friday that the Biden administration is "deeply troubled" by the experimental execution of a man in Alabama through the use of nitrogen gas and expressed concerns about the death penalty.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Kenneth Eugene Smith, 58, was executed Thursday night by breathing pure nitrogen gas through a face mask, a controversial method of capital punishment &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/alabama-first-state-execute-prisoner-using-pure-nitrogen-setting-off-debate-death-penalty-methods" target="_blank"&gt;used for the first time&lt;/a&gt; in the U.S. that causes oxygen deprivation. The execution method, which has been slammed for being inhumane and a form of torture, comes after a last-minute appeal to halt the death penalty from being carried out in this case was rejected by the Supreme Court.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"The reports of Kenneth Smith and his death last night obviously is very troubling," Jean-Pierre told reporters at a press briefing. "It is very troubling to us as an administration, it is very troubling to us here at the White House."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This was the first time that a new execution method had been used in the U.S. since lethal injection, which is now the most commonly used form of capital punishment, was introduced in 1982.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/alabama-death-row-inmate-executed-nitrogen-gas-nations-first-new-method-42-years" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALABAMA DEATH ROW INMATE EXECUTED WITH NITROGEN GAS, NATION'S FIRST BY A NEW METHOD IN 42 YEARS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The execution lasted about 22 minutes and Smith appeared to remain conscious for several minutes. For at least two minutes, he appeared to shake and writhe on the gurney, sometimes pulling against the restraints, before several minutes of heavy breathing until breathing was no longer perceptible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"The president has long said and has had deep deep concerns with how the death penalty is implemented and whether it is consistent … with our values," she continued. "So, we are deeply troubled by it, by Kenneth Smith's death. And so, you know, it is just troubling to hear."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Smith faced the death penalty for the 1988 murder-for-hire stabbing death of a preacher's wife, Elizabeth Sennett, who was found dead in the home she shared with her husband in Colbert County. Prosecutors said Smith was one of two men who were each paid $1,000 to kill Sennett on behalf of her husband, who was in huge debt and wanted to collect insurance money.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Her husband, Charles Sennett Sr., killed himself when the investigation began looking at him as a possible suspect. The other man &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/crime" target="_blank"&gt;convicted in the killing&lt;/a&gt; was executed in 2010.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Alabama attempted to execute Smith by lethal injection in 2022 but failed to carry it out because of issues with inserting an IV into his veins, the second time in two months and the third since 2018 that the state was unsuccessful in putting an inmate to death.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/alabama-death-row-inmate-facing-nitrogen-hypoxia-execution-loses-last-ditch-appeal" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALABAMA DEATH ROW INMATE FACING NITROGEN HYPOXIA EXECUTION LOSES LAST DITCH APPEAL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Republican Gov. Kay Ivey announced the day after Smith's failed execution that executions would be paused to allow an internal review of lethal injection procedures. Lethal injections in Alabama resumed last summer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In Smith's last-minute appeal to the Supreme Court on Thursday to block his execution, he argued that his death sentence should not be carried out over the potential for the state to botch the procedure following the first failed attempt to put him to death. The court rejected the appeal but Justice Sonia Sotomayor wrote in a dissenting opinion that &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/us-regions/southeast/alabama" target="_blank"&gt;Alabama was using Smith&lt;/a&gt; as a "guinea pig" to test a new method of execution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The United Nations and European Union condemned Smith's experimental execution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"He was writhing and clearly suffering," U.N. Human Rights Office spokesperson Ravina Shamdasani said at a U.N. briefing. "Rather than looking for novel, untested methods to execute people, let’s just bring an end to the death penalty. This is an anachronism that doesn’t belong in the 21st century."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The U.N. Human Rights Office previously warned that it believed the capital punishment method "could breach the prohibition on torture or other cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment or punishment."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The European Union said in a statement Friday that nitrogen hypoxia was "particularly cruel and unusual punishment" and urged states to "move toward abolition, in line with the worldwide trend."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 2021, Attorney General Merrick Garland imposed a moratorium on the federal death penalty, a move that President Biden supports.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"[Smith's execution] underscores why the president supports the attorney general's moratorium on the federal death penalty, pending review of the policies and procedures governing its use," Jean-Pierre said Friday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But despite the moratorium, federal prosecutors said earlier this month they will seek the death penalty against the gunman who in May 2022 killed 10 black people at a grocery store in Buffalo, New York.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"The President always has had deep concerns with how the death penalty is implemented," Jean-Pierre said. "He always has."&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/KJP5.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">afb95820-d44d-51c4-a799-5fe7bcd09744</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/white-house</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/southeast/alabama</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/crime</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/crime/police-and-law-enforcement</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 03:53:42 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-touts-potential-border-deal-senate-speaker-mike-johnson-says-bill-dead-on-arrival-house</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-touts-potential-border-deal-senate-speaker-mike-johnson-says-bill-dead-on-arrival-house</guid>
      <title>Biden touts potential border deal with Senate as Speaker Mike Johnson says bill 'dead on arrival' in House</title>
      <description>President Biden wants Republican lawmakers to support a bill to aid Ukraine while enacting reforms to secure the southern border, but House Speaker Mike Johnson says such a bill would be &amp;quot;dead on arrival.&amp;quot;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/joe-biden" target="_blank"&gt;President Biden&lt;/a&gt; on Friday appeared to tout negotiations between his administration with the Senate to address the crisis on the southern border despite House Speaker Mike Johnson saying such legislation would be "dead on arrival" in his chamber.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a statement released by the White House, Biden urged Congress to support a bipartisan package that would tie border security measures with aid to Ukraine. He said the terms negotiated with senators would be the "toughest and fairest" set of reforms ever to secure the border.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"It would give me, as President, a new emergency authority to shut down the border when it becomes overwhelmed," he said. "And if given that authority, I would use it the day I sign the bill into law."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/illegal-migrants-are-sleeping-in-terminals-of-boston-airport-on-daily-basis-as-crisis-overwhelms-shelters" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ILLEGAL MIGRANTS ARE SLEEPING IN TERMINALS OF BOSTON AIRPORT ON ‘DAILY BASIS’ AS CRISIS OVERWHELMS SHELTERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hours earlier, Johnson wrote a letter to his colleagues in the Senate signaling the legislation addressing &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration/border-security" target="_blank"&gt;the border&lt;/a&gt; and aid to Ukraine has no future in the House if Republicans there feel it doesn't do enough to address the records numbers of illegal immigrants crossing into the United States.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I wanted to provide a brief update regarding the supplemental and the border, since the Senate appears unable to reach any agreement. If rumors about the contents of the draft proposal are true, it would have been dead on arrival in the House anyway," Johnson wrote. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I am emphasizing again today that House Republicans will vigorously oppose any new policy proposal from the White House or Senate that would further incentivize illegal aliens to break our laws," he added. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A bipartisan group of lawmakers has been trying to secure a deal for months with White House officials to unlock $60 billion of aid to assist &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/defense/wars" target="_blank"&gt;Ukraine's war&lt;/a&gt; with Russia that's included in the national security supplemental bill. The Department of Defense has already depleted its available funds earmarked for Ukraine without needing approval from Congress. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Biden administration is seeking over $100 billion in funding, including $14 billion for the border. But Republicans have demanded limits on migrant releases into the interior, including the use of parole, and negotiators have been attempting to find a compromise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/download" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;CLICK HERE TO GET THE FOX NEWS APP&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/executive/white-house" target="_blank"&gt;White House&lt;/a&gt; statement, Biden urged lawmakers to provide funding to aid Ukraine that was requested in October, which would include funds for an additional 1,300 U.S. Border Patrol agents, 375 immigration judges, 1,600 asylum officers and more than 100 inspection machines to help prevent the smuggling of fentanyl into the United States. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"For everyone demanding tougher border control, this is the way to do it," Biden said. "If you're serious about the border crisis, pass a bipartisan bill and I will sign it."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fox News Digital's Jamie Joseph, Tyler Olson and Aishah Hasnie contributed to this report. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2023/10/931/523/johnson-biden.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">47e72823-35e8-5eaa-a552-a0ea6f30f741</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/border-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/house-of-representatives</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/illegal-immigrants</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/mike-johnson</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-business/</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 21:33:38 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-taunts-trump-invoking-former-first-ladys-be-best-anti-bullying-campaign</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-taunts-trump-invoking-former-first-ladys-be-best-anti-bullying-campaign</guid>
      <title>Biden taunts Trump by invoking former first lady’s ‘Be Best’ anti-bullying campaign</title>
      <description>President Biden took a personal jab at former President Trump Friday, posting &amp;quot;Be Best&amp;quot; to a repost of a news article on X, in a reference to the former first lady Melania Trump&amp;apos;s anti-bullying campaign.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/joe-biden" target="_blank"&gt;President Biden&lt;/a&gt; taunted former President Trump late Friday by invoking the name of former first lady Melania Trump’s "Be Best" anti-cyberbullying campaign while responding to a report that his campaign has been throwing jabs at the Republican frontrunner. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Be Best," Biden simply wrote on his official X, formerly Twitter, account after reposting an online report that claimed Trump has been "rattled" by Biden increasingly personally insulting him on the campaign trail. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The video had originally been posted by the Biden campaign’s digital rapid response channel on X. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The CNN report claimed that Biden was attempting to throw &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/video/6345361058112" target="_blank"&gt;Trump off-message&lt;/a&gt; by calling him a "loser" and emphasizing the "former" in former president. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-campaign-attack-ad-blames-trump-dobbs-abortion-decision" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIDEN CAMPAIGN ATTACK AD BLAMES TRUMP FOR DOBBS ABORTION DECISION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Senior Trump adviser Jason Miller sent Fox News Digital a statement over Biden's post that said: "This Tweet wasn’t posted by Joe Biden. Everybody knows Biden goes to bed at 4pm, and this was posted after 6pm. But to the staffer who posted this on Biden’s behalf, maybe you should focus more on reducing inflation and fixing the chaos you’ve created on our Southern Border rather than trying to be cute."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Biden also referred to Trump as Herbert Hoover — who was president during the Great Depression — and teased "Good one, Donald" on X on Monday after reposting a report from his campaign that contrasted Trump’s claim that the stock market would crash if Biden was president with it hitting &lt;a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/markets/dow-blows-past-38000-in-new-milestone" target="_blank"&gt;"all-time record highs"&lt;/a&gt; this week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-fires-back-says-biden-true-threat-democracy" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRUMP FIRES BACK AT JAN. 6 CRITICISM, SAYS BIDEN IS A ‘TRUE THREAT TO DEMOCRACY’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He also poked fun at Trump having seemingly &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-mixes-up-nikki-haley-with-nancy-pelosi-at-new-hampshire-rally" target="_blank"&gt;confused Republican presidential candidate Nikki&lt;/a&gt; Haley with former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi at a recent New Hampshire rally, posting, "I don’t agree with Nikki Haley on everything, but we agree on this much: She is not Nancy Pelosi." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And after Trump won the Iowa caucuses on Jan. 15, Biden posted a video saying, despite so many Republicans trying to beat him, "I’m still the person to ever beat Donald Trump and I’m looking forward to doing it again." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/download" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLICK HERE TO GET THE FOX NEWS APP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The former first lady launched "Be Best" in 2018, saying the goal was to help children get, "the tools they need to cultivate their social and emotional health. I feel strongly as adults we can and should be best at educating our children about the importance of a healthy and balanced life." &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/biden-melania-trump.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">877f2de3-d012-52db-821f-06af9678e983</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/donald-trump</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 20:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/nikki-haley-slams-trump-defamation-trial-verdict-not-talking-about-border-inflation</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/nikki-haley-slams-trump-defamation-trial-verdict-not-talking-about-border-inflation</guid>
      <title>Nikki Haley slams Trump after defamation trial verdict: 'Not talking about' border, inflation</title>
      <description>Nikki Haley criticized former President Donald Trump after he was ordered to pay $83.3 million to E. Jean Carroll following his civil trial Friday in New York City.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/nikki-haley" target="_blank"&gt;Nikki Haley&lt;/a&gt; criticized former President Trump on Friday, saying he is too preoccupied with other issues, hours after he was ordered to pay E. Jean Carroll more than &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-ordered-pay-more-80-million-e-jean-carroll-defamation-trial" target="_blank"&gt;$80 million in damages&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/donald-trump" target="_blank"&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt; wants to be the presumptive Republican nominee and we’re talking about $83.3 million in damages," Haley wrote on X. "We’re not talking about fixing the border. We’re not talking about tackling inflation. America can do better than Donald Trump and Joe Biden."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Earlier, a jury said Trump should pay Carroll over defamatory statements in which he disparaged her while denying allegations that he raped her at the Bergdorf Goodman department store across from Trump Tower in Manhattan sometime in 1996.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-takes-stand-testify-defense-e-jean-carroll-trial" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRUMP DEFENDS HIMSELF ON THE STAND, BLASTS E JEAN CARROLL TRIAL: 'THIS IS NOT AMERICA'&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump is running against Biden for a second term in the White House despite being entangled in multiple lawsuits and criminal cases. He criticized Friday's verdict on social media. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Absolutely ridiculous! I fully disagree with both verdicts, and will be appealing this whole Biden Directed Witch Hunt focused on me and the Republican Party," Trump posted on his TRUTH Social shortly after the verdict was read. "Our Legal System is out of control, and being used as a Political Weapon. They have taken away all First Amendment Rights." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"THIS IS NOT AMERICA!" he added. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Haley has emerged as Trump's remaining major rival for the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/elections/republicans" target="_blank"&gt;Republican nomination&lt;/a&gt;. He defeated her in Tuesday's New Hampshire primary, and before that, won the Iowa caucus, where Haley placed third.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Friday, she questioned Trump's &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/health/mental-health" target="_blank"&gt;mental state&lt;/a&gt;, asking whether he was "confused again" after releasing a video showing him railing against the court proceedings in New York.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the video, Trump is seen blasting someone his campaign said was Carroll. He said he has "no idea" who she is, before referencing "somebody running for office."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Wait a second, did Trump just say the person suing him is 'running for office?' Is he confused again? I was not in a New York City courtroom yesterday, any more than I was in charge of security at the Capitol on January 6. I was in South Carolina meeting with voters. They’d like to see a debate between me and Trump," Haley wrote in a post on X.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fox News Digital's Brandon Gillespie contributed to this report. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/865afa3a-Haley-Trump.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">6683f34e-0f16-5fb6-88ed-3a9bc81433f6</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/nikki-haley</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/donald-trump</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/newsedge/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 20:11:07 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/white-house-establishes-guidelines-cabinet-notifications-austins-hospitalization-controversy</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/white-house-establishes-guidelines-cabinet-notifications-austins-hospitalization-controversy</guid>
      <title>White House establishes guidelines for Cabinet notifications following Austin's hospitalization controversy</title>
      <description>The White House has established guidelines for Cabinet heads&amp;apos; delegation of duties in the wake of Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin&amp;apos;s secret hospitalization.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/executive/white-house" target="_blank"&gt;White House&lt;/a&gt; this week established a new set of guidelines for when Cabinet heads are unable to do their job and have to delegate authority. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The new rules come in the wake of the revelation earlier this month that the Pentagon failed to notify the White House for several days of &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/defense/secretary-of-defense" target="_blank"&gt;Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin&lt;/a&gt;'s hospitalization and surgery for prostate cancer in late December. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Following the communications fiasco — and even some calls for&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/white-house-responds-gop-calls-sec-austins-resignation-mystery-ailment-hospitalization" target="_blank"&gt; Austin to resign&lt;/a&gt; — the White House conducted a review, asking each Cabinet department for its notification process before revealing its new guidelines Friday. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The guidelines, obtained by Fox News, include notifying the offices of cabinet affairs and White House chief of staff, "when agencies anticipate or are preparing for a delegation of authority and again when the delegation occurs," documenting in writing that the delegation of authority is in effect and the acting authority needs to contact its counterpart in the White House, according to a memo from White House Chief of Staff Jeff Zients sent to Cabinet Secretaries. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/defense-secretary-austin-resign-grave-errors-hospitalization-says-congressman" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEFENSE SECRETARY AUSTIN SHOULD RESIGN OVER ‘GRAVE ERRORS’ IN HOSPITALIZATION, SAYS CONGRESSMAN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Notably, Zients' memo added, that a delegation of authority is also required when the Cabinet member is in "limited or no access to communication, undergoing hospitalization or a medical procedure requiring general anesthesia, or otherwise in a circumstance when he or she may be unreachable."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/defense-secretary-lloyd-austin-called-testify-before-congress-secretive-hospitalization" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEFENSE SECRETARY LLOYD AUSTIN CALLED TO TESTIFY BEFORE CONGRESS ABOUT SECRETIVE HOSPITALIZATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Austin was first admitted to Walter Reed National Military Medical Center in Bethesda, Maryland, on Dec. 22 for prostate surgery, then taken back to the hospital after he developed an infection a week later. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It was days before the White House was notified and Congress, the press and the public didn’t hear about it until Jan. 5. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Friday, Austin visited doctors at Walter Reed for a "for a scheduled post-prostatectomy surveillance appointment."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Walter Reed Dr. John Maddox and Dr. Gregory Chesnut said in a statement that Austin "continues to recover well and is expected to make a full recovery."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/download" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLICK HERE TO GET THE FOX NEWS APP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Secretary Austin's prostate cancer was treated early and effectively, and his prognosis is excellent. Beyond planned physical therapy and regular post-prostatectomy follow-up appointments, he has no planned further treatment for his cancer."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A U.S. Defense official told Fox News on Friday that Austin is expected to be back at &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/defense/pentagon" target="_blank"&gt;the Pentagon&lt;/a&gt; on Monday after recovering from his surgery and working at home since Jan. 15.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fox News' Pat Ward contributed to this report. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/lloyd-austin.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">bbc1cddc-d5c1-5d7d-ba8b-705aad861b32</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/white-house</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/defense/secretary-of-defense</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/defense/pentagon</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 19:11:15 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-biden-business-associate-rob-walker-says-joe-biden-never-involved-business-dealings</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-biden-business-associate-rob-walker-says-joe-biden-never-involved-business-dealings</guid>
      <title>Hunter Biden business associate Rob Walker says Joe Biden was 'never involved' in business dealings</title>
      <description>Hunter Biden business associate Rob Walker told congressional investigators on Friday that President Biden was “never involved in any of&amp;quot; his son’s business activities.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hunter Biden business associate &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-biden-biz-associate-rob-walker-testify-being-alleged-vehicle-biden-familys-foreign-funds" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Walker&lt;/a&gt; told congressional investigators on Friday that President Biden was "never involved in any of" his son’s business activities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Walker testified for hours before the House Oversight and Judiciary Committees after being &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-biden-biz-associate-rob-walker-testify-being-alleged-vehicle-biden-familys-foreign-funds" target="_blank"&gt;subpoenaed&lt;/a&gt; to do so last year. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Walker arrived at 10 a.m. ET. When he left just before 6 p.m., he told reporters: "I answered questions to the best of my ability." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-biden-biz-associate-rob-walker-testify-being-alleged-vehicle-biden-familys-foreign-funds" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HUNTER BIDEN BIZ ASSOCIATE ROB WALKER TO TESTIFY ON BEING ALLEGED 'VEHICLE' FOR BIDEN FAMILY'S FOREIGN FUNDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fox News Digital obtained a copy of Walker’s opening statement, in which he testified under oath that the allegations against the president and the first son are "unfounded," but welcomed the opportunity to "provide context to some of the events that are frequently the public focus of the members of these committees."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Walker said he and Hunter "became friends" during the Clinton administration in 1999 and began working together around 2008 by "developing business with, and consulting for, various individuals, businesses, and NGO’s (non-governmental organizations)."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Walker said Hunter "is an intelligent, caring, and generous person, and his demeanor and strong interpersonal skills made him a valued and effective business partner."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He also said Hunter "lost his way" when his brother, Beau Biden, "became seriously ill" and later passed away.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I’m glad he’s recovering and hope he and his family are doing well," Walker said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He went on to detail his business with Hunter, saying the opportunities they pursued together were "varied, varied, well-founded, and well within the bounds of legitimate business activities."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"To be clear, President Biden — while in office or as a private citizen — was never involved in any of the business activities we pursued. Any statement to the contrary is simply false," Walker testified. "Hunter made sure there was always a clear boundary between any business and his father. Always."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He added: "And as his partner, I always understood and respected that boundary." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Walker said that he is "very concerned" that his testimony "may be taken out of context to further a political objective, rather than to discover the truth."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/six-additional-biden-family-members-may-have-benefited-from-hunter-business-dealings-comer-says" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;6 ADDITIONAL BIDEN FAMILY MEMBERS 'MAY HAVE BENEFITED' FROM HUNTER BUSINESS DEALINGS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I therefore respectfully ask that any public statements about this interview be accompanied by the release of the entire transcript of what I say here today, so that members of the public can form their own conclusions about what did and did not happen during my business relationship with Hunter," he said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Walker's testimony came as part of the House impeachment inquiry against President Biden. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hours into his transcribed interview, House Judiciary Committee Chairman Jim Jordan, R-Ohio, told reporters that Walker testified that "a couple of weeks after Joe Biden leaves the vice presidency, Hunter Biden and his team, these guys, do business with, enter a contract with, this affiliate of CEFC, the Chinese energy company." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Jordan said "a few days later there's a lunch at the Four Seasons" that CEFC executives, Hunter, James Gilliar and Walker attended. Jordan said, "Joe Biden stops and gives a presentation." Jordan said days later, $3 million was sent to Walker from the Chinese company. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I think that's just the timing, just a sequence," Jordan said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In notifying his attorney of his subpoena in November, Jordan and House Oversight Committee Chairman James Comer, R-Ky., explained that Walker set up his limited liability company, Robinson Walker LLC. The chairmen said it was "used as a vehicle to receive foreign funds and send a percentage of the money to Biden family members."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One example Comer and Jordan provided is when Joe Biden served as vice president, Robinson Walker LLC received millions of dollars from a company owned by Gabriel Popoviciu, a Romanian who was then the subject of a high-profile corruption prosecution in his home country.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-family-received-more-1m-hunter-associate-2017-china-wire-house-oversight" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;BIDEN FAMILY RECEIVED MORE THAN $1M FROM HUNTER ASSOCIATE AFTER 2017 CHINA WIRE: HOUSE OVERSIGHT&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Following the receipt of this money, Robinson Walker sent over one million dollars to Biden family accounts, including those of Hunter Biden and Hallie Biden," Comer and Jordan wrote.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But Comer and Jordan flagged that those payments from Romania to Robinson Walker LLC started "within approximately five weeks of then-Vice President Biden meeting with the President of Romania, where, according to the official readout, the issue of corruption was discussed."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When asked what Hunter did for Popoviciu, Walker told the committee that Hunter flew to Romania to meet with U.S. Ambassador to Romania Hans Klemm, who had just been confirmed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/house-oversight-subpoenas-hunter-biden-james-biden-rob-walker-testimony-impeachment-inquiry" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;HOUSE OVERSIGHT SUBPOENAS HUNTER BIDEN, JAMES BIDEN, ROB WALKER FOR TESTIMONY AMID IMPEACHMENT INQUIRY&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Comer and Jordan also note that Robinson Walker LLC received the payment of $3 million from State Energy HK Limited, a Chinese company, in February 2017, less than two months after Biden left the Obama administration. Comer and Jordan said that in the three months following that payment, Robinson Walker LLC made "incremental payments totaling over one million dollars to Biden family members and their companies, including Hallie Biden and entities associated with Hunter Biden and James Biden."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to an FBI FD-302 form detailing Walker's 2021 interview with Special Counsel David Weiss' team and obtained by the House Ways and Means Committee, Walker said the "$3 million amount was more of a ‘thank you’ from CEFC." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Comer and Jordan, in subpoenaing Walker, said he may be able to provide evidence relevant to the impeachment inquiry, saying that Walker "played a key role in the Biden family’s business dealings and the chain of complex financial transactions that was used to hide the foreign sources of the funds received by the Biden family."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After receiving money from the CEFC entity in March 2017, Walker testified Hunter told him to send payments to his uncle, James Biden, and sister-in-law, Hallie Biden, even though they did not do work for the CEFC entity. Further, James Biden wanted a piece of the CEFC entity money despite not being involved in the deal. Walker called Hunter to approve the money transfer to James Biden. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2023/06/931/523/AP23177027348831.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">903f7125-5488-5030-81f6-7f71fa914547</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/hunter-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 18:49:09 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/rnc-files-election-integrity-lawsuit-mississippi-challenging-ballot-counting-deadlines</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/rnc-files-election-integrity-lawsuit-mississippi-challenging-ballot-counting-deadlines</guid>
      <title>RNC files an election integrity lawsuit in Mississippi challenging ballot counting deadlines</title>
      <description>The RNC filed a lawsuit Friday to stop Mississippi ballots received days after Election Day from being counted, arguing the current statute violates federal law.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIRST ON FOX — &lt;/strong&gt;The Republican National Committee filed a lawsuit Friday to &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/us-regions/southeast/mississippi" target="_blank"&gt;stop Mississippi ballots&lt;/a&gt; received days after Election Day from being counted, arguing a current statute violates federal law. The state's current deadline allows ballots postmarked on or before Election Day to be counted if received within five business days of the election. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/elections/republicans" target="_blank"&gt;The RNC&lt;/a&gt;, along with the Mississippi Republican Party and the Hinds County Republican Party, are claiming the practice violates the federal Election Day statute, which states that "the Tuesday next after the 1st Monday in November, in every even numbered year, is established as the day for the election."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Federal law is very clear. Election Day is the Tuesday after the first Monday in November. However, some states accept and count ballots days and days after Election Day, and we believe that practice is wrong," RNC Chairwoman Ronna McDaniel told Fox News Digital.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/entertainment/events/in-court" target="_blank"&gt;We are filing this lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; because counting ballots that are received well after polls have closed could undermine voter confidence in elections."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/rnc-chair-mcdaniel-tells-fox-news-we-need-unite-around-trump" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RNC CHAIR MCDANIEL TELLS FOX NEWS 'WE NEED TO UNITE' AROUND TRUMP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Mississippi lawsuit could have major implications on how other states conduct their elections. The RNC is inovlved in 74 &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/state-and-local/elections" target="_blank"&gt;election integrity lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; in 22 states, in addition to mobilizing thousands of poll watchers in dozens of battleground states ahead of Election Day in November. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The RNC also launched "Bank Your Vote" websites in all 50 states to educate Republicans how to vote early, request a ballot and find voting locations. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/rnc-launches-bank-your-vote-websites-16-languages-across-all-50-states-ahead-gop-primaries" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RNC LAUNCHES 'BANK YOUR VOTE' WEBSITES IN 16 LANGUAGES ACROSS ALL 50 STATES AHEAD OF GOP PRIMARIES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The majority of Trump supporters say they have no confidence in vote counting and reporting in the upcoming 2024 presidential election, according to a recent &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/01/04/jan-6-trump-voters-believe-fraud-2024/72072407007/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;USA Today/Suffolk University Poll.&lt;/a&gt; In addition, two-thirds of Trump supporters believe Biden was not legitimately elected in 2020. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/democratic-party" target="_blank"&gt;The Democratic National Committee&lt;/a&gt; has been fighting election integrity laws in swing states. On Wednesday, the Biden campaign scored a legal victory in North Carolina after the Democrats won a lawsuit filed to block an election law that would require photo ID and address verification for voters registering on the day of the election. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2023/11/931/523/vote-stickers.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">216732fd-d9f8-5e1c-97bb-cb2180acda8c</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/republicans</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/southeast/mississippi</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/newsedge/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/voter-fraud-concerns</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/voting</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/state-and-local/elections</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 18:31:30 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/migrant-crisis-broke-new-record-in-december-with-302k-encounters-officials-confirm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/migrant-crisis-broke-new-record-in-december-with-302k-encounters-officials-confirm</guid>
      <title>Migrant crisis broke new record in December with 302k encounters, officials confirm</title>
      <description>There were over 302,000 migrant encounters at the southern border in December, Customs and Border Protection officials confirmed in a Friday afternoon release.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;December broke records for migrant encounters at the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration/border-security" target="_blank"&gt;southern border&lt;/a&gt;, Customs and Border Protection (CBP) confirmed on Friday, as it released numbers showing that there were a record 302,000 migrant encounters at the southern border.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Friday afternoon release, which showed 302,034 encounters in December, comes more than three weeks since Fox reported that there were over 302,000 encounters -- which breaks the monthly record set in September and is the first time the number has ever breached the 300,000 mark.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s enough people to fill the Las Vegas Super Bowl more than four and a half times, and is nearly the total population of Cincinnati. Of the encounters, nearly 250,000 were between ports of entry. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/border-patrol-has-no-plans-remove-razor-wire-set-up-texas-amid-feud-biden-admin" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BORDER PATROL HAS ‘NO PLANS’ TO REMOVE RAZOR WIRE SET UP BY TEXAS AMID FEUD WITH BIDEN ADMIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s the latest staggering numbers to come from the southern border since the crisis exploded in 2021. There were over 2.4 million migrant encounters in FY 23, after a record-setting FY 22. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The numbers do not include "gotaways" of which there have been estimates of over 800,000 in FY 23, or migrants who are paroled in through the Cuban, Haitian, Nicaraguan and Venezuelan (CHNV) parole program -- which allows 30,000 migrants to fly directly in each month as part of the Biden administration’s "expanded lawful pathways."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Separately, there were 19 individuals arrested on the terror watch list in December – all on the southern border. It brings the total for FY 24 so far to 50 arrests (49 on the southern border, one on the northern border).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/abbott-declares-texas-right-self-defense-from-migrant-invasion-amid-feud-with-biden-admin" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;ABBOTT DECLARES TEXAS HAS ‘RIGHT TO SELF-DEFENSE’ FROM MIGRANT ‘INVASION’ AMID FEUD WITH BIDEN ADMIN&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The watch list, now officially called the Terrorist Screening Dataset, is the U.S. database that contains information on terrorist identities and includes not only known or suspected terrorists but also affiliates of watch-listed individuals.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The numbers come as border security remains a red-hot political issue across the country. &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/border-patrol-has-no-plans-remove-razor-wire-set-up-texas-amid-feud-biden-admin" target="_blank"&gt;In Texas&lt;/a&gt;, officials are feuding with the federal government over the state’s seizure of Shelby Park and the administration’s cutting of razor wire set up by Texas. The Supreme Court recently allowed the Biden administration to resume the practice.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, multiple "sanctuary" cities have called for aid from the Biden administration for the massive numbers of migrants they are seeing flood into their cities, some of whom have been bused in by Texas.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Separately, in Washington D.C., negotiations are ongoing over a border supplemental bill. The White House has requested $14 billion as part of its request, including for aid to communities, more staffing and increased expedited removal. Republicans have said the package needs to include asylum restrictions and limits on the administration’s use of humanitarian parole.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Biden administration has said it needs comprehensive immigration reform from Congress as well as funding to deal with what it says is a "broken" system, and has accused Republicans of seeking to turn it into a political issue. It has also pointed to a number of removals since May that is larger than the entirety of FY 2019, and record fentanyl seizures.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Friday, acting CBP Commissioner Troy Miller said that CBP "remains vigilant to respond to the serious challenges we are experiencing across the southwest border."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"CBP continues to use all available resources to ensure the safety and security of our agents and officers, and the migrants who are often misled and victimized by the transnational criminal organizations," he said. "But as we have repeatedly said, CBP and our federal partners need additional support from Congress so that we can continue to effectuate consequences for those who do not use established lawful pathways."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But Republicans have blamed the crisis on the Biden administration and its policies, and has recently moved to impeach &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/executive/homeland-security" target="_blank"&gt;DHS Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas&lt;/a&gt; over what they have claimed is a "dereliction of duty." Those calls were immediately renewed after the numbers dropped, with House Homeland Security Chair Mark Green saying they were "undeniable proof" of his majority’s case.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"This staggering number of encounters at our borders only happens by design and a willful refusal to comply with the laws passed by Congress," he said. "The harsh reality is that this secretary has intentionally opened our borders, sending a clear message worldwide: entering this country illegally means release into the interior, with little to no chance of removal—and the world has responded accordingly. This is intentional, and it is a disaster. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/Texas-border-migrants.gif" type="image/gif" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">b4f3ce1b-a01e-5084-b26e-8572202d3379</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/border-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/homeland-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/illegal-immigrants</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 17:33:31 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/fox-news-politics-jury-orders-trump-pay-massive-damages</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/fox-news-politics-jury-orders-trump-pay-massive-damages</guid>
      <title>Fox News Politics: Jury orders Trump to pay massive damages</title>
      <description>The latest updates from the 2024 campaign trail, exclusive interviews and more Fox News politics content</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to Fox News’ Politics newsletter with the latest political news from Washington D.C. and updates from the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/elections" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;2024 campaign trail&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/newsletters" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Subscribe now to get Fox News Politics newsletter in your inbox&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;What's happening?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;- GOP moves to defund sanctuary cities&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;- Biden approval rating hits rock bottom &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;- Dem calls out soft-on-crime prosecutors&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Former President Trump was &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-ordered-pay-more-80-million-e-jean-carroll-defamation-trial" target="_blank"&gt;ordered to pay over $83 million&lt;/a&gt; in damages to E. Jean Carroll after she sued him for what she called defamatory statements following her accusation that he sexually assaulted her.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The trial was not about whether Trump sexually assaulted Carroll – a jury in a Manhattan civil trial last year already found Trump liable for the alleged assault, which Trump vehemently denies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Absolutely ridiculous!" Trump wrote on Truth Social after the verdict came down. "I fully disagree with both verdicts, and will be appealing this whole Biden Directed Witch Hunt focused on me and the Republican Party," Trump posted on his TRUTH Social shortly after the verdict was read. "Our Legal System is out of control, and being used as a Political Weapon. They have taken away all First Amendment Rights." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump added: "THIS IS NOT AMERICA!"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'PLAYING POLITICS'&lt;/strong&gt;: White House halts enormous natural gas projects in victory for environmentalists &lt;a href="https://foxnews.com/politics/white-house-halts-enormous-natural-gas-projects-victory-environmentalists" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GATHERING INFORMATION&lt;/strong&gt;: Hunter Biden biz associate Rob Walker to testify on being alleged 'vehicle' for Biden family's foreign funds &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-biden-biz-associate-rob-walker-testify-being-alleged-vehicle-biden-familys-foreign-funds" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘HONOR OF A LIFETIME’&lt;/strong&gt;: First-ever chief White House diversity advisor leaving Biden administration &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/first-ever-chief-white-house-diversity-advisor-leaving-biden-administration" target="_blank"&gt;…&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt; m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHUT IT DOWN&lt;/strong&gt;: Democrats blast impeachment inquiry after GOP witness says he is 'unaware' of Joe Biden role in family biz &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/democrats-blast-impeachment-inquiry-gop-witness-unaware-joe-biden-role-family-biz" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'THREATEN OUR KIDS': &lt;/strong&gt;Eric Swalwell calls out soft-on-crime prosecutors for letting 'dangerous people threaten' kids&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/eric-swalwell-calls-out-soft-on-crime-prosecutors-for-letting-dangerous-people-threaten-our-kids" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'DICTATORS'&lt;/strong&gt;: Sen. Tillis schools anti-Israel protester on Hamas in hallway confrontation &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/sen-tillis-schools-anti-israel-protester-on-hamas-in-hallway-confrontation" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'HEIGHT OF HYPOCRISY': &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;GOP lawmaker moves to defund ‘sanctuary’ cities, slams ‘hypocrisy’ as they seek federal aid for migrant crisis&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/gop-lawmaker-moves-defund-sanctuary-cities-slams-hypocrisy-they-seek-federal-aid-migrant-crisis" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EMOTIONALLY TAXING&lt;/strong&gt;: House GOP leaders look to Dems for help on $80B tax bill as Republicans defect &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/house-gop-leaders-eye-democrats-help-80b-tax-bill-republicans-defect" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'GRAVE CONCERN'&lt;/strong&gt;: House members press Biden to withdraw radical 'judicial' nominee with ties to 9/11 hijacker sympathizers &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/house-members-press-biden-to-withdraw-court-nominee-with-ties-to-9-11-hijacker-sympathizers-grave-concerns" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'SOME RACIST IN THEM':&lt;/strong&gt; Alabama congressman says everyone 'has some type of racist in them' during debate: report&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/alabama-congressman-everyone-some-type-racist-them-during-debate-report" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BORDERLINE&lt;/strong&gt;: Speaker Johnson says House will vote on impeaching Mayorkas 'as soon as possible' &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/speaker-johnson-says-house-vote-impeaching-mayorkas-soon-possible" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'DESIGNED' NOT TO SOLVE CRISIS?&lt;/strong&gt;: Senate GOP in 'quandary' over border security, Ukraine aid package &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/senate-gop-in-quandary-over-border-security-ukraine-aid-package" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'SHORTSIGHTED EFFORT'&lt;/strong&gt;: Dozens of Senate Republicans warn Biden's latest war on energy empowers America's enemies &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/dozens-senate-republicans-warn-bidens-latest-war-energy-empowers-americas-enemies" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'MORE FREEDOM'&lt;/strong&gt;: Fetterman rejects top Democrat's attempted crackdown on Zyn: 'On the side of more freedom' &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/fetterman-rejects-top-democrats-attempted-crackdown-zyn" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SINKING SOON&lt;/strong&gt;: Biden's approval rating lowest for third-year president since Carter &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/bidens-approval-rating-lowest-third-year-president-since-carter" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPEAKING OUT&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump opposes plan to pressure RNC into making him the GOP's 'presumptive nominee' &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-opposes-plan-pressure-rnc-making-gops-presumptive-nominee" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'A LOT CAN GO SIDEWAYS'&lt;/strong&gt;: Nonpartisan watchdog releases report outlining top election security threats for 2024 &lt;a href="https://foxnews.com/politics/nonpartisan-watchdog-releases-report-outlining-top-election-security-threats-for-2024-a-lot-can-go-sideways" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRUMP TRAIN&lt;/strong&gt;: Several senior House Republicans still silent on Trump 2024 amid growing pressure for party unity &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/several-senior-house-republicans-still-silent-trump-2024-growing-pressure-party-unity" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'DEPLOY THEIR GUARDS'&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump urges states to surge National Guard to Texas as Abbott standoff with Biden accelerates &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-urges-states-surge-national-guard-texas-abbott-standoff-with-biden-accelerates" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SELF-ADMINISTERED DEATH&lt;/strong&gt;: Minnesota lawmakers initiate debate on physician-assisted suicide bill &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/minnesota-lawmakers-initiate-debate-physician-assisted-suicide-bill" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOT COMPLIANT&lt;/strong&gt;: Texas AG Ken Paxton says state won’t comply with Biden administration order to reopen park to federal agents &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/texas-attorney-general-ken-paxton-state-wont-comply-biden-administration-order-reopen-park-federal-agents" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get the latest updates from the 2024 campaign trail, exclusive interviews and more on &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="https://foxnews.com/politics" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;FoxNews.com&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/7c6f2d86-trump-court.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">8a779bad-a12b-593a-b283-eb88ee9b33e2</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/columns/elections-newsletter</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 17:24:47 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/maryland-bill-would-ban-gun-carry-owners-without-insurance-policy-least-300k</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/maryland-bill-would-ban-gun-carry-owners-without-insurance-policy-least-300k</guid>
      <title>Maryland bill would ban gun carry for owners without insurance policy of at least $300K</title>
      <description>A Maryland House Democrat introduced a bill last week banning gun owners from carrying their firearm without at least $300,000 of liability insurance.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/personal-freedoms/second-amendment" target="_blank"&gt;Gun owners in&lt;/a&gt; Maryland would be required to buy at least $300,000 in liability insurance or forfeit their ability to carry a firearm under a new bill.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The controversial legislation, introduced by Delegate Terri Hill, D-Howard County, would prohibit the "wear or carry" of a gun anywhere &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/us-regions/northeast/maryland" target="_blank"&gt;in the state&lt;/a&gt; unless the individual has obtained a liability insurance policy of at least $300,000.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"A person may not wear or carry a firearm unless the person has obtained it and is covered by liability insurance issued by an insurer authorized to do business in the State under the Insurance Article to cover claims for property damage, bodily injury, or death arising from an accident resulting from the person’s use or storage of a firearm or up to $300,000 for damages arising from the same incident, in addition to interest and costs," the proposed Maryland legislation said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/red-states-nra-backed-bill-allow-armed-teachers-classroom-one-step-closer-passage"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RED STATE'S NRA-BACKED BILL TO ALLOW ARMED TEACHERS IN CLASSROOM ONE STEP CLOSER TO PASSAGE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to the proposed law, &lt;a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/category/insurance" target="_blank"&gt;the liability insurance&lt;/a&gt; requirement does not apply to members of the military or federal law enforcement officers. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is also an insurance exemption if a gun is unloaded.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hill told &lt;a href="https://foxbaltimore.com/amp/news/local/maryland-bill-would-force-gun-owners-to-get-300k-liability-insurance-to-wear-or-carry-md-terri-hill-annapolis-second-amendment-firearm-rights-regulations-2a-nra-conceal-clyde-boatwright-police-officers" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;FOX 45 News&lt;/a&gt; that this bill is an attempt to pass "common sense" gun control.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/maryland-countys-gun-safety-pamphlet-law-upheld-federal-appeals-court"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MARYLAND COUNTY'S GUN SAFETY PAMPHLET LAW UPHELD IN FEDERAL APPEALS COURT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;She told the local outlet that the idea came after talking to a concerned constituent who said that gun owners should "bear some liability in cases where there is damage because of guns being used in ways that cause harm."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Gun advocate Frank Duffy noted to the outlet that the legislation is yet another effort to hinder individuals from carrying their firearms.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"It’s another effort &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/us-regions/northeast/maryland" target="_blank"&gt;by the state&lt;/a&gt; to throw an obstacle in front of people trying to get their conceal carry permits," Duffy said. "The Supreme Court made a decision that said Maryland and other states could not require a good or substantial reason to get a permit."&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2021/03/931/523/Concealed-Carry-iStock.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">75f2305d-8b72-5e6e-8faf-10a9ec624760</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/personal-freedoms/second-amendment</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/northeast/maryland</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 17:24:11 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/top-white-house-adviser-migration-issues-leaving-intense-southern-border-policy-blowback</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/top-white-house-adviser-migration-issues-leaving-intense-southern-border-policy-blowback</guid>
      <title>Top White House adviser on migration issues leaving amid intense southern border policy blowback</title>
      <description>A senior National Security Council advisor on migration issues is leaving as the White House faces fierce criticism over the situation at the Southern Border.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Katie Tobin, a top &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/executive/white-house" target="_blank"&gt;White House&lt;/a&gt; adviser on migration issues, is leaving after three years within the National Security Council, according to reports. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tobin had originally planned to leave her position as senior director for &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration/border-security" target="_blank"&gt;transborder security&lt;/a&gt; last summer, but the Biden administration persuaded her to stay on through the end of the year, NBC News reported.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tobin’s departure comes as the administration faces intense criticism over its handling of migrants illegally crossing the southern border.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tobin was part of a U.S. delegation that traveled to Mexico to discuss what can be done to decrease illegal crossings, and she led planning for the end of the Trump era &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/senate-border-bill-allow-5000-migrants-day-before-title-42-limit-starts" target="_blank"&gt;Title 42&lt;/a&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/texas-faces-potential-federal-standoff-state-ag-border-looks-like-biden-cut-deal-cartels" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AS TEXAS FACES POTENTIAL FEDERAL STANDOFF, STATE AG SAYS BORDER LOOKS LIKE BIDEN ‘CUT A DEAL WITH CARTELS’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan called Tobin "tenacious and dedicated" on migration efforts in a statement to NBC News. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He added, "We will miss Katie’s positivity and thoughtful contributions on an incredibly complex portfolio, but wish her well." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fox News Digital has reached out to the White House and National Security Council for comment. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/governor-pledges-ship-border-razor-wire-biden-stops-abbott" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOEM PLEDGES TO SHIP RAZOR WIRE TO TEXAS IF BIDEN STOPS ABBOTT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A replacement for Tobin has not been selected, an NSC spokesperson told NBC News. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Just this week, Border Patrol agents near El Paso, Texas, &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/border-patrol-catches-40-illegal-migrants-stuffed-several-vehicles" target="_blank"&gt;caught 40 migrants&lt;/a&gt; involved in two human smuggling operations as the border hit its highest rate of migrant encounters last month, blowing away previous statistics. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sources with &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration" target="_blank"&gt;Customs and Border Protection&lt;/a&gt; told Fox News Digital that migrant encounters hit a staggering 300,000 incidents in the last month of 2023, reaching a level thought unimaginable just years ago.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Between Dec. 1 and 31, more than 302,000 migrants were documented attempting to cross the U.S. &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration/mexico" target="_blank"&gt;southern border&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/download" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLICK HERE TO GET THE FOX NEWS APP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is the highest total for a single month ever recorded. It is also the first time migrant encounters have exceeded 300,000.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fox News' Michael Dorgan contributed to this report. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/migrants-on-mexico-side-of-border.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">83da3a8b-7deb-5e01-bd53-c8fa5bec98af</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/border-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/white-house</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/southwest/texas</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 17:12:16 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-ordered-pay-more-80-million-e-jean-carroll-defamation-trial</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-ordered-pay-more-80-million-e-jean-carroll-defamation-trial</guid>
      <title>Trump ordered to pay more than $80 million in E. Jean Carroll defamation trial</title>
      <description>Jury reaches verdict in the civil defamation lawsuit against Trump, stemming from E. Jean Carroll’s defamation lawsuit claiming he sexually attacked her in a department store dressing room in the 1990s.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A federal jury decided former President Trump must pay E. Jean Carroll more than $83 million in damages after he denied allegations he raped her in the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The jury decided Trump must pay $18.3 million in compensatory damages, and $65 million in punitive damages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Federal Judge Lewis A. Kaplan announced the jury's verdict Friday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-takes-stand-testify-defense-e-jean-carroll-trial" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRUMP DEFENDS HIMSELF ON THE STAND, BLASTS E JEAN CARROLL TRIAL: 'THIS IS NOT AMERICA'&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A federal jury in New York City decided last year that Trump was not liable for rape, but was liable for sexual abuse and defamation. The former president was ordered to pay $5 million in that trial.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Absolutely ridiculous! I fully disagree with both verdicts, and will be appealing this whole Biden Directed Witch Hunt focused on me and the Republican Party," Trump posted on his TRUTH Social shortly after the verdict was read. "Our Legal System is out of control, and being used as a Political Weapon. They have taken away all First Amendment Rights." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump added: "THIS IS NOT AMERICA!"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Carroll, who alleged that Trump raped her at the Bergdorf Goodman department store across from Trump Tower in Manhattan sometime in 1996, was seeking $12 million.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump, the 2024 GOP frontrunner, has repeatedly and vehemently denied the allegation. His denial resulted in Carroll slapping Trump with a defamation lawsuit, claiming that his response caused harm to her reputation. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The jury found Carroll was injured as a result of statements Trump made while in the White House in June 2019. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The jury awarded Carroll $7.3 million in compensatory damages, other than the reputational repair program, and $11 million in damages for the reputational repair program. The jury found Trump’s statements were made to harm Carroll and awarded her $65 million in punitive damages. In total, the jury said Carroll should be paid $83.3 million. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump took the stand briefly on Thursday in his defense. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;First, Trump was asked whether he saw his deposition played in court, to which he replied: "Yes." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Second, he was asked if he stands by his statements in the deposition, to which he replied: "100 percent. Yes."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And third, he was asked if he ever threatened Carroll in his tweets and social media posts. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"No," Trump said. "I was only defending myself from what I believe was a false allegation." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The judge struck statements from Trump that went beyond a yes or no answer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the way out of the courtroom, Trump repeatedly said: "This is not America."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump and his legal team insist that Carroll's allegations are fabricated, with the former president's initial reaction including an accusation that Carroll was motivated by wanting to sell copies of her book. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump has repeatedly told Fox News Digital that he has "absolutely no idea who this woman is." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump, on his Truth Social account on Friday after closing arguments, posted that Judge Kaplan "refuses to allow the Anderson Cooper Interview on CNN of E. Jean Carroll wherein Carroll says, ‘Rape is sexy,' and numerous other things that totally exonerate me." Trump was referring to possible evidence being introduced in the trial. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Judge Kaplan is refusing me my Constitutional Right to Due Process, to defend myself against this False Accusation," Trump wrote. "This is a one-sided trial, where the other side is allowed everything, and we are allowed nothing. He is an extremely abusive individual, the likes of which few have seen before!"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump, also on his Truth Social account last week, posted images of Carroll’s tweets dating back to 2015. In one image, Carroll wrote: "How do you know your ‘unwanted sexual advance’ is unwanted, until you advance it?"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trump also posted that Carroll "has been ‘all over the place’ on the timing of this alleged ‘incident,’ which never took place, and is being coached by Lunatic Radical Left Democrat operative attorney, Roberta Kaplan, who has sued me before, and just lost."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I am the only one who has been injured by this attempted EXTORTION," Trump posted.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is a developing story. Please check back for updates. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/e-jean-carroll.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">165566d2-df57-5f95-947d-91ba5d6955a0</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/donald-trump</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 16:46:35 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/former-new-york-governor-andrew-cuomo-sexually-harassed-thirteen-staffers-justice-department</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/former-new-york-governor-andrew-cuomo-sexually-harassed-thirteen-staffers-justice-department</guid>
      <title>Former New York Gov Andrew Cuomo sexually harassed 13 staffers, Justice Department says</title>
      <description>Former New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo subjected more than a dozen women to a sexually hostile work environment, the Justice Department said Friday.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Former New York &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/person/andrew-cuomo" target="_blank"&gt;Gov. Andrew Cuomo&lt;/a&gt; subjected at least 13 female state employees to a "sexually hostile work environment," according to a settlement agreement reached between the Justice Department and New York State Executive Chamber.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The agreement resolves claims of sexual harassment and retaliation against Cuomo, a Democrat, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/justice-department" target="_blank"&gt;DOJ release&lt;/a&gt; on Friday. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The nine-page agreement said Cuomo subjected the female employees to unwelcome, non-consensual sexual contact, "ogling" and gender-based nicknames. His senior staff was aware of the then-governor's behavior and retaliated against four women," the settlement states. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/bill-maher-confronts-cuomo-nursing-home-scandal-ex-ny-gov-calls-questions-monday-morning-quarterbacking" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;BILL MAHER CONFRONTS CUOMO ON NURSING HOME SCANDAL, EX-NY GOV CALLS QUESTIONS ‘MONDAY MORNING QUARTERBACKING’&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"The Executive Chamber’s response was designed only to protect Cuomo from further accusations, rather than to protect employees from sexual harassment," the settlement states. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a statement, Cuomo's attorney, Rita Glavin, said he didn't harass anyone and that the DOJ investigation was based on a "deeply flawed, inaccurate, biased, and misleading report" by New York State Attorney General Letitia James. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"This is nothing more than a political settlement with no investigation," Glavin said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cuomo is &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/andrew-cuomo-sues-letitia-james-sexual-harassment-investigation-documents" target="_blank"&gt;suing James&lt;/a&gt; for documents related to her 2021 investigation into alleged sexual harassment that led to his resignation in August 2021 following her bombshell report of his alleged misdeeds. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/former-ny-governor-reemerges-critic-dems-far-left-policies-fueling-comeback-speculation" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FORMER NY GOVERNOR RE-EMERGES AS CRITIC ON DEMS' FAR-LEFT POLICIES, FUELING COMEBACK SPECULATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a separate statement, Cuomo spokesperson Rich Azzopardi said the DOJ's investigation "isn’t worth the paper it’s printed on."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mariann Wang, an attorney for two women who alleged Cuomo harassed them, said: "We are pleased the US Attorney’s office and the Executive Chamber have taken serious steps to ensure nothing like the abuse Cuomo engaged in will happen again."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"We hope these measures have real impact and prevent the kind of repeated abuse of power that resulted in so much harm to so many women," she added. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;U.S. Rep. Elise Stefanik, R-New York, criticized Cuomo and his denial of the sexual harassment allegations. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"While Cuomo and his deranged sycophant enforcers are desperately trying to resurrect and rewrite their heinous legacy of lies, innocent lives lost, and rampant abuse, even the DOJ confirms that Andrew Cuomo is a corrupt criminal who illegally harassed women and retaliated against them while Governor."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/download" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLICK HERE TO GET THE FOX NEWS APP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Under the terms of the settlement, New York Gov. Kathy Hochul's office will create a new process for complaints against senior officials and will have to create an "anti-retaliation monitoring policy."&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2023/01/931/523/andrew_cuomo.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">4c238d87-d645-5f1e-a8e5-401717100420</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/andrew-cuomo</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/justice-department</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/northeast/new-york</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/entertainment/genres/crime</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 16:13:56 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/border-patrol-has-no-plans-remove-razor-wire-set-up-texas-amid-feud-biden-admin</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/border-patrol-has-no-plans-remove-razor-wire-set-up-texas-amid-feud-biden-admin</guid>
      <title>Border Patrol has 'no plans' to remove razor wire set up by Texas amid feud with Biden admin</title>
      <description>U.S. Border Patrol has a strong relationship with Texas officials, and will not be cutting razor wire except in emergencies, a senior official tells Fox News.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/us/immigration/border-security" target="_blank"&gt;Border Patrol&lt;/a&gt; has "no plans" to remove razor wire placed by Texas along the southern border, a senior Customs and Border Protection (CBP) official told Fox News on Friday, stressing a "strong" relationship with Texas despite an ongoing legal battle between the state and the administration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Texas is currently locked in a multi-pronged legal fight with the federal government over the security of the Texas-Mexico border. The federal government has threatened legal action over Texas’ recent seizure of Shelby Park near Eagle Pass, while lawsuits are ongoing over the administration’s cutting of razor wire set up by Texas and the establishment of buoys in the Rio Grande. Texas has declared that it has a right to "self-defense" against what it says is a migrant "invasion."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Monday, &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/texas-ag-paxton-promises-fight-not-over-after-scotus-rule-biden-admins-razor-wire-cutting"&gt;&lt;u&gt;the Supreme Court&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; found in the administration's favor when it granted an emergency appeal to allow agents to keep cutting border wire set up by Texas after a lower court had blocked such moves. Texas has continued to fortify the border, and has also indicated it will not comply with the administration’s demands for it to vacate the Shelby Park area.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/abbott-declares-texas-right-self-defense-from-migrant-invasion-amid-feud-with-biden-admin" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABBOTT DECLARES TEXAS HAS ‘RIGHT TO SELF-DEFENSE’ FROM MIGRANT ‘INVASION’ AMID FEUD WITH BIDEN ADMIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"[President Biden's] actions have caused an unprecedented invasion that we must defend against," Abbott said on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Biden administration has said that Texas is interfering with the federal enforcement of immigration law.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Enforcement of immigration law is a federal responsibility," a DHS spokesperson said this week. "Rather than helping to reduce irregular migration, the State of Texas has only made it harder for frontline personnel to do their jobs and to apply consequences under the law. We can enforce our laws and administer them safely, humanely, and in an orderly way."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dozens of Republican governors have backed Texas as the feud between the state and the feds escalates. But a senior CBP official told Fox that the relationship between Texas and Border Patrol officials on the ground is "strong."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"While this issue plays out in the courts, the relationship between Border Patrol, Texas DPS [Department of Public Safety], &amp;amp; TMD [Texas Military Dept.] remains strong," the official said. "Our focus is and will always be the mission of protecting this country and its people. On the ground, we continue to work alongside these valuable partners in that endeavor."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Bottom line: Border Patrol has no plans to remove infrastructure (c-wire) placed by Texas along the border. Our posture remains the same. If we need to access an area for emergency response, we will do so. When that happens, we will coordinate with Texas DPS &amp;amp; TMD"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/texas-ag-paxton-promises-fight-not-over-after-scotus-rule-biden-admins-razor-wire-cutting" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;TEXAS AG PAXTON PROMISES ‘FIGHT IS NOT OVER’ AFTER SCOTUS RULE ON BIDEN ADMIN'S RAZOR WIRE CUTTING &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That sentiment was echoed by the Border Patrol union, which in a lengthy statement dismissed the idea that Border Patrol agents could start arresting Texas National Guard members.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"TX NG and rank-and-file BP agents work together and respect each other's jobs. Period. If TX NG members have LAWFUL orders, then they have to carry out those orders," the &lt;a href="https://x.com/BPUnion/status/1750942606274797850?s=20" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;National Border Patrol Council&lt;/a&gt; said on X, formerly known as Twitter.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Rank-and-file BP agents appreciate and respect what TX has been doing to defend their state in the midst of this catastrophe that the Biden Admin has unleashed on America," the statement said. "We want to be perfectly clear, there is no fight between rank-and-file BP agents and the TX NG, Gov. Abott, or TX DPS. It may make flashy headlines, but it simply isn't true."&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/2442843d-border.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">787e3d6f-3c9d-5341-aca5-b77c5df42c86</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/us-regions/southwest/texas</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/border-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration/illegal-immigrants</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/immigration</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/homeland-security</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 16:05:03 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/kirby-unsure-dollar-figure-us-funding-controversial-un-agency-allegedly-tied-hamas-attack</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/kirby-unsure-dollar-figure-us-funding-controversial-un-agency-allegedly-tied-hamas-attack</guid>
      <title>Kirby unsure of ‘dollar figure’ of US funding to controversial UN agency allegedly tied to Hamas attack</title>
      <description>White House National Security Council spokesman John Kirby was pressed Friday about the amount of money the U.S. has given to UNRWA, which is now under review.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;White House National Security Council spokesman John Kirby said Friday that he was unsure of a specific "dollar figure" when asked about the amount of money the U.S. has given to a United Nations agency that is facing allegations that some of its members were involved in Hamas’ October 7 &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/world/world-regions/israel" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;&lt;u&gt;attack on Israel.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Kirby made the comment during an exchange with Fox News White House correspondent Peter Doocy after the State Department announced earlier today that the U.S. is "extremely troubled" by claims that a dozen members of the United Nations Relief and Works Agency (UNRWA) for Palestine Refugees in the Near East "may have been involved" in &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/world/terrorism" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Hamas’ attack.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The State Department has since "temporarily paused additional funding" for UNRWA pending a review.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"It certainly looks as if there's cause to be concerned about the actions of some of the members of UNRWA . . . but that does not and nor should it impugn the entire agency and the entire body of work that they're doing." Kirby said. "They have helped save literally thousands of lives in Gaza. They do important work. [It] doesn't mean that there aren’t some folks in that group that need to be punished for potentially these kinds of behavior." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"That's bad, though, if there are 12 people who are accused," Doocy said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/world/biden-admin-cuts-funding-controversial-un-agency-allegations-members-assisted-hamas-massacre" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;BIDEN ADMINISTRATION CUTS FUNDING TO CONTROVERSIAL UN AGENCY OVER ALLEGATIONS MEMBERS ASSISTED IN HAMAS MASSACRE&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"It's bad, it's bad if there's one. Bad if there's one," Kirby responded. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"And the U.S. is giving them money, how much money?" Doocy then asked. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"We have suspended the, we have suspended," Kirby started saying before Doocy asked, "How much before the suspension?" &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"I don't have the dollar figure for you, Peter. I'll take the question and get back to you. But we have suspended unallocated funds pending the outcome of the investigation," Kirby concluded. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/world/uns-top-court-orders-israel-adhere-genocide-convention-not-cease-attacks-preliminary-ruling" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;UN’S TOP COURT ALLOWS ISRAEL TO KEEP FIGHTING IN GAZA, ORDERS IT TO ‘ADHERE TO THE GENOCIDE CONVENTION’&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The U.S. funding to the agency will resume subject to an investigation from the &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/world/united-nations" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;&lt;u&gt;United Nations.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;UNRWA, citing information provided by Israeli authorities, terminated the contract with the accused employees on Friday and announced an investigation "to protect the agency’s ability to deliver humanitarian assistance" and "establish the truth without delay," Reuters reported. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The U.S. State Department in a press release said that Secretary of State Antony Blinken spoke with U.N. Secretary-General António Guterres regarding the investigation, which will be "comprehensive and independent." The U.S. insisted that it must see "complete accountability for anyone who participated in the heinous attacks of Oct. 7." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fox News’ Peter Aitken contributed to this report. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/John-Kirby.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">d08681dd-57ae-51bf-9cae-f96c6ee98039</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/white-house</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/world/world-regions/israel</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/world/terrorism</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/world/conflicts</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/foreign-policy/middle-east</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 16:01:37 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/sugar-brother-kevin-morris-loaned-hunter-biden-6-5m-debts-back-taxes-more-previous-estimate</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/sugar-brother-kevin-morris-loaned-hunter-biden-6-5m-debts-back-taxes-more-previous-estimate</guid>
      <title>'Sugar brother' Kevin Morris loaned Hunter Biden $6.5M for debts and back taxes, more than previous estimate</title>
      <description>Kevin Morris loaned Hunter Biden approximately $6.5 million — more than originally estimated and discussed, his attorney revealed in a letter this week.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-biden-lawyer-testifies-first-trump-impeachment-created-emergency-file-unpaid-taxes" target="_blank"&gt;Kevin Morris&lt;/a&gt; loaned Hunter Biden approximately $6.5 million — over $1 million more than originally estimated and discussed, his attorney revealed in a letter this week. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fox News obtained a letter &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-biden-lawyer-testifies-first-trump-impeachment-created-emergency-file-unpaid-taxes" target="_blank"&gt;Kevin Morris’&lt;/a&gt; attorney sent to the House Oversight Committee this week. The letter shows a breakdown of the loans and when Morris wants those loans repaid.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/house-oversight-kevin-morris-gave-massive-financial-support-raising-campaign-finance-concerns" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;KEVIN MORRIS GAVE 'MASSIVE' FINANCIAL SUPPORT TO HUNTER BIDEN, RAISING CAMPAIGN FINANCE CONCERNS: COMER&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Morris was subpoenaed to appear before the committee for a transcribed interview as part of the House impeachment inquiry.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;During his interview, Morris testified that he loaned Hunter Biden at least $5 million and began paying his tax liability.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Morris and his attorney were estimating during the interview, a source told Fox News, and promised to follow-up with exact figures loaned to the first son.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The letter outlines an additional $1.6 million more than Morris had estimated during the interview.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Morris, on Oct. 13, 2021, gave Hunter Biden a loan for approximately $1.4 million. According to the letter, Hunter Biden was to repay the loan, with $500,000 paid by Oct. 1, 2026 and the remaining $417, 634 by Oct. 1, 2027, plus interest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A few days later, Morris loaned Hunter Biden $2.6 million, with directions to repay the loan by Oct. 1, 2029. That loan, according to Morris’ lawyer, "was used to pay, among other debts, Mr. Biden’s tax debt to the IRS."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Oct. 17, 2022, Morris loaned Hunter Biden $640,355 to be repaid by Oct. 15, 2027.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/hunter-biden-lawyer-testifies-first-trump-impeachment-created-emergency-file-unpaid-taxes" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HUNTER BIDEN LAWYER TESTIFIES THAT 1ST TRUMP IMPEACHMENT CREATED 'EMERGENCY' TO FILE UNPAID TAXES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Dec. 30, 2022, Morris loaned Hunter $685,813.99, to be repaid by Oct. 15, 2027.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Dec. 29, 2023, Morris loaned Hunter approximately $1.2 million to be repaid by Oct. 15, 2028, with all interest paid by October 2029.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"As negotiated by separate attorneys for Mr. Morris and Mr. Biden, each of these notes has an interest rate of 5%, a set payment term, and were negotiated by separate attorneys for Mr. Morris and Mr. Biden," the letter states.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the letter, Morris’ attorney, whose name is redacted, claimed House Oversight Committee Chairman James Comer and "other members" have ignored "the request we made to refrain from mischaracterizing Mr. Morris’ testimony in a public statement." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"One more time—I am asking that this letter and its information not be released out of its context of the questions and answers Mr. Morris gave at his transcribed interview on January 18, 2024," the attorney wrote. "Nothing in this letter shall be considered a waiver of any of my client’s rights, objections, or claims, all of which are expressly reserved." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Morris told the House panel last week that "With respect to the loans, I am confident that Hunter will repay. I did not and do not have any expectations of receiving anything from Hunter's father or the Biden administration in exchange from helping Hunter, nor have I asked for anything from President Biden or his administration."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Special Counsel David Weiss charged Biden with nine federal tax charges, which break down to three felonies and six misdemeanors for &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/category/politics/finance/taxes" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;$1.4 million in owed taxes&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that have since been paid.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Weiss charged Hunter in December, alleging a "four-year scheme" in which the president's son did not pay his federal income taxes from January 2017 to October 2020 while also filing false tax reports.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hunter Biden pleaded not guilty to all charges.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Weiss also indicted the first son on federal gun charges in Delaware last year. Hunter Biden pleaded not guilty to those charges as well. His attorneys are attempting to have that case dismissed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fox News' Lee Ross contributed to this report. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2024/01/931/523/KevinMorris-HunterBiden.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="931" height="523"/>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">00d0c600-6c7d-5c3f-93b5-b9d391d4bb50</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">Fox News</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/hunter-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/person/joe-biden</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/house-of-representatives/republicans</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 15:56:20 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>